<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Angelo Stavrow</title>
    <link>https://angelostavrow.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Angelo Stavrow</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-CA</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 05:45:07 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://angelostavrow.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Glitch Project Name Lottery</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/glitch-project-name-lottery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 05:45:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/glitch-project-name-lottery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://glitch.com&#34;&gt;Glitch&lt;/a&gt; creates randomized project names when you remix a project, and they look something like &lt;code&gt;adjective-noun.glitch.me&lt;/code&gt;. You can always rename these later, but oftentimes they’re just too amusing to bother (I’m looking at you, &lt;code&gt;victorious-beer&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what if you decided that you were going to remix the node starter app, and then had to spend a couple of hours building an app based purely on the random name you were assigned?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, you’d end up with something like &lt;a href=&#34;https://glitch.com/~therapeutic-caribou&#34;&gt;Therapeutic Caribou&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d been poking at &lt;a href=&#34;https://textblob.readthedocs.io/en/dev/&#34;&gt;TextBlob&lt;/a&gt; in Python over the weekend. Why not find an npm module that handles sentiment analysis to create a little app that takes in what you’re saying and replies based on how positive or negative the sentiment is. I’m using the &lt;a href=&#34;http://winkjs.org/wink-sentiment/&#34;&gt;wink-sentiment&lt;/a&gt; module to do this in analyzer.js, but it should be fairly easy to swap out any other analysis module in the &lt;code&gt;rankSentiment()&lt;/code&gt;  function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while we’re at it, why not make it so that you’re just talking to the web app, rather than typing? I’ve been working through Wes Bos’ &lt;a href=&#34;https://javascript30.com&#34;&gt;JavaScript30&lt;/a&gt; course and, as luck would have it, just went through the native &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/SpeechRecognition&#34;&gt;SpeechRecognizer&lt;/a&gt; project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that this is something that I threw together in a couple of hours, it’s very far from complete — our therapeutic caribou is a pretty lousy conversationalist, there are a couple of bugs around SpeechRecognizer events, and the design is… well, pretty unpleasant. Additionally, I’ve only tested this in Chrome, so I have no idea if it works as expected in other browsers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all that said, it was still a lot of fun to throw something together that let me play with a bit of both client- and server-side JavaScript, some neat native technologies like SpeechRecognizer, and some interesting concepts like sentiment analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you try playing the Glitch Project Name Lottery, let me know what you come up with!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And we&#39;re back</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/and-were-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 15:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/and-were-back/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been almost four months since I last wrote something. I&amp;rsquo;ve been pretty busy over the last little while completely overhauling this site, and there are a few changes that I&amp;rsquo;d like to point out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From here on out, this will be the home of my personal blog. All article from &lt;a href=&#34;http://makebeforebreak.com/&#34;&gt;Make Before Break&lt;/a&gt; have been imported here; any new long-form writing will be posted to this site, and here only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Short updates will continue to be posted to my &lt;a href=&#34;https://angelo.micro.blog/&#34;&gt;microblog&lt;/a&gt;, which is syndicated to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AngeloStavrow&#34;&gt;my Twitter account&lt;/a&gt;. I generally reply to anyone who &lt;code&gt;@&lt;/code&gt;-mentions me on either service, but I tend to spend more time in my RSS reader than my Twitter timeline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site runs a custom-built &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; theme I built. I based this theme on some &lt;a href=&#34;../../philosophy.txt&#34;&gt;beliefs&lt;/a&gt; about what a website should be like in 2018. The work here isn&amp;rsquo;t quite done yet, so please let me know if you see anything amiss. You can find out more about this on &lt;a href=&#34;../../about&#34;&gt;the about page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it for now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--references--&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Messy Journeys and Scruffy Role Models</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/messy-journeys-and-scruffy-role-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/messy-journeys-and-scruffy-role-models/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tell me if any of this sounds familiar:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why am I having such a hard time with this? What&amp;rsquo;s wrong with me?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maybe I’m not smart enough to do this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People hired me to do this work, but I&amp;rsquo;m never going to figure this out. I&amp;rsquo;m a fraud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are at least a couple of common threads with these statements, but I think the most interesting one is that each of these statements is an implicit comparison that I&amp;rsquo;m making between myself and someone that&amp;rsquo;s, y&amp;rsquo;know, good at what they do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when you&amp;rsquo;re trying something new, it can be really hard to remember that you&amp;rsquo;re &lt;em&gt;trying something new&lt;/em&gt;. We approach new things with expectations, adn we typically want to feel smart, we want to believe that we&amp;rsquo;re good at stuff. Eventually, though, Reality pops in for a visit to remind us that we haven&amp;rsquo;t done this before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sorry to rain on your parade there, but this&amp;hellip; this isn&amp;rsquo;t going to be a cakewalk for you. Here, have a brick wall!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when you run face-first into a brick wall you feel, well, not very smart. Someone else would have noticed that wall. I don&amp;rsquo;t know what I&amp;rsquo;m doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Desirae Odjick wrote a great article at Half Banked on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.halfbanked.com/learning-about-money/&#34;&gt;learning about money&lt;/a&gt; that I think touches a bit on this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What makes you feel confident with money?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot I could say about it, including that building knowledge over time has been helpful, as has seeking out both expert opinions and people “in real life” who are willing to be open with me about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I did that over ten years, at different paces based on where I was in my life. “Start ten years ago,” isn’t exactly the most actionable advice out there, ya know?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;rsquo;m tackling something new, it often feels like I have &lt;em&gt;so much&lt;/em&gt; catching up to do. And, sure, if the best time to start was ten years ago, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/joy-and-pain/201504/the-best-time-plant-tree-was-20-years-ago-no-matter&#34;&gt;the second best time to start is right now&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But here&amp;rsquo;s the thing with comparing yourself to a ten-year veteran in the field, or comparing your first app to stuff that&amp;rsquo;s won Apple Design Awards or whatever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’re not real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt;, anyways — at least not outside of the reality you create for them in your head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building up the confidence to &lt;em&gt;just get started&lt;/em&gt; on something new is hard, and it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;especially&lt;/em&gt; hard when you&amp;rsquo;re comparing yourself to other folks that have years of experience doing what you&amp;rsquo;re struggling to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so in your augmented reality that you create for these experts and the fruits of their labour, you can&amp;rsquo;t see the ten years of hard work. The string of failures. The moments of self-doubt and being on the precipice of giving up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s why, when it comes to learning, &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/glitch/celebrating-the-creative-process-warts-and-all-342336679d19&#34;&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s nice to see a map of the whole confused, messy journey&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The slick, polished look of the app and its refactored, tidied-up codebase doesn’t tell the real story about how it was created. It skips the hours spent digging into that elusive bug, the time stuck while crafting a particularly tricky piece of logic, and the endless UI tweaks to get it looking just right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You company&amp;rsquo;s engineering journal on all the cool things that went into your 1.0? That&amp;rsquo;s awesome. Your slick and polished app? Amazing. Your talk on best practices for using, I dunno, whatever JavaScript framework is cool these days? Inspirational.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when I sit down to try my hand at creating something, it&amp;rsquo;s comforting to have seen that great things aren’t just &lt;em&gt;born that way&lt;/em&gt;. Seeing the gaffes and the dead-end experiments that didn&amp;rsquo;t make it into the final artifact is reassuring: when they happen to you, they feel less like failures, less like monumental wastes of time, and more like a part of the learning process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And therein lies the rub, the disconnect: we talk up the value of learning from others&amp;rsquo; mistakes, and then put in all kinds of effort to scrub clean that which we put out into the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe that&amp;rsquo;s doing us all a disservice. Maybe that&amp;rsquo;s to be expected in an age where we focus on social &lt;em&gt;media&lt;/em&gt; over &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_learning_theory&#34;&gt;social &lt;em&gt;learning&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, but maybe we can do better —and &lt;em&gt;get&lt;/em&gt; better— by being a little bit less perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Reference links --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>App Store Reviews in Manuscript</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/app-store-reviews-in-manuscript/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 04:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/app-store-reviews-in-manuscript/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve got some iOS apps as side projects (they&amp;rsquo;re in dire need of updates, but that&amp;rsquo;s neither here nor there). To keep things organized, I use a &lt;a href=&#34;https://manuscript.com&#34;&gt;Manuscript&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;em&gt;née&lt;/em&gt; FogBugz) account that I opened six years ago for planning work and, more relevant to this post, to capture (almost) all customer feedback. There&amp;rsquo;s a custom mailbox set up with an email address in my business domain, to which customers can send questions and comments about the apps.
These emails generate cases that I use for correspondence, and I can then open feature requests, bug reports, and known issues as linked cases in the relevant project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I say &amp;ldquo;almost&amp;rdquo; all customer feedback, though, because not everything gets captured in Manuscript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s missing? You don&amp;rsquo;t get notification emails from Apple for new App Store reviews, so I can&amp;rsquo;t pipe these into Manuscript. Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t that be nice? Instead, you have to check for new reviews manually, across App Stores in all countries where your app is sold, or rely on yet another service. I don&amp;rsquo;t know about you, but I&amp;rsquo;ve got enough inboxes to deal with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/make-better-software/how-to-get-started-making-manuscript-integrations-6da236b68f98&#34;&gt;Manuscript integrations&lt;/a&gt;, powered by &lt;a href=&#34;https://glitch.com&#34;&gt;Glitch&lt;/a&gt;. At their core, integrations let you create microservices in Glitch that communicate between Manuscript and some external service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And thus came the idea for this project: since every app on the App Store (and Mac App Store) has an RSS feed of its reviews, I could create an integration that checks your app’s feed and, if there’s something new, pull it into a new case in Manuscript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be working on this in &lt;a href=&#34;https://glitch.com/~app-store-reviews-in-manuscript&#34;&gt;Glitch&lt;/a&gt;, and tracking it in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AngeloStavrow/app-store-reviews-in-manuscript&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. As of the time of this writing, the Glitch project is just a remix of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://glitch.com/edit/#!/hello-manuscript&#34;&gt;sample Manuscript integration&lt;/a&gt;, but the work has been planned out; I’ve set a release date of March 25&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; for v1.0 of the integration, giving me two weeks to build and test the thing. While I’m not especially concerned about the ship date slipping, not having any ship date &lt;em&gt;at all&lt;/em&gt; usually means that a project doesn’t get any priority on my calendar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week was all about defining the project itself and the work to be undertaken, and this week is about getting started on the actual code. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested, you can read over the draft &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AngeloStavrow/app-store-reviews-in-manuscript/wiki/functional-spec&#34;&gt;functional spec&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AngeloStavrow/app-store-reviews-in-manuscript/wiki/technical-spec&#34;&gt;technical spec&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s open sourced under the MIT license. I’ll be working on this in the open, which I have feelings about (read: &lt;em&gt;anxiety and trepidation&lt;/em&gt;), and I’ve also set up a development journal in &lt;a href=&#34;http://dayoneapp.com&#34;&gt;Day One&lt;/a&gt;, where I add short weekly retrospectives on wins and losses for the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More to come as I make progress against the milestone!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Links --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remote Work: Year One</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/remote-work-year-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 05:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/remote-work-year-one/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks ago, Julia Evans &lt;a href=&#34;https://jvns.ca/blog/2018/02/18/working-remotely--4-years-in/&#34;&gt;wrote a retrospective&lt;/a&gt; on what it’s been like working remotely that resonated with me, given that today is my one-year anniversary since taking a remote position. Since this is my first fully-remote job, taking some time to reflect on how things have gone seems like a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia answered some great questions about working remotely, so I’ll do the same here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-s-scary-about-working-remote&#34;&gt;What’s scary about working remote?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, not very much, though that certainly depends on who you&amp;rsquo;re working for and your own comfort levels with all kinds of things. I&amp;rsquo;d worked from home a fair bit prior to going fully remote, so I knew I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have issues with productivity. I thought there might be difficulty in bonding with colleagues, or missing out on the hallway and/or watercooler talk, but that hasn&amp;rsquo;t been a thing (more on that later).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there&amp;rsquo;s a downside, it&amp;rsquo;s that it&amp;rsquo;s really easy (for me, anyway) to slip into a place where I don&amp;rsquo;t leave the house and don&amp;rsquo;t get in any social interaction or physical activity. I have to force myself to be deliberate about those things now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-s-good-about-working-remote&#34;&gt;What’s good about working remote?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number one benefit of working remotely is having the ability to focus. Oh, wow, is it ever awesome to be able to set yourself up with the perfect work environment, and know that you (for the most part) don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about being an hour deep into researching or working on something only to get tapped on the shoulder or interrupted by noisy coworkers. We&amp;rsquo;ve reconfigured our second bedroom to be my private office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The commute isn&amp;rsquo;t bad, either. During my engineering degree, I had to turn down an internship at the Canadian Space Agency because I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t afford to buy a car to commute back and forth (or move closer to their location, either). That sucked, and it made me realize just how messed up it is that working &lt;em&gt;can cost you money&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;let-s-talk-about-career-development&#34;&gt;Let’s talk about career development.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a bit hard to address, as I&amp;rsquo;ve spent most of my first year just trying to learn the ropes and become a productive member of the team. I haven&amp;rsquo;t taken advantage of things like our conference and education budget, so I&amp;rsquo;m aiming to be better at this in year two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-do-you-learn-from-your-colleagues-remotely&#34;&gt;How do you learn from your colleagues remotely?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean, picking someone&amp;rsquo;s brain is never more than a Slack conversation away, but we recently trialed a new mentorship program. I got to learn a lot about working on web applications/in JavaScript under the tutelage of a really smart and experienced developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also use &lt;a href=&#34;https://manuscript.com&#34;&gt;Manuscript&lt;/a&gt; as a store of knowledge, so learning from colleagues is never more than a few searches away — detailed notes in cases can serve up a whole lot of learnin&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-you-stay-plugged-into-spontaneous-conversations-around-the-office&#34;&gt;How do you stay plugged into spontaneous conversations around the office?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With something like two-thirds of the company remote, most conversations happen in Slack. Tuning in to the right channels (and getting your notifications right so that you&amp;rsquo;re not interrupted when you&amp;rsquo;re heads down) makes it easy enough to understand what&amp;rsquo;s going on, but it did take a while to get that right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-you-have-idle-watercooler-discussions&#34;&gt;How do you have idle/watercooler discussions?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of our developers created a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/STRd6/coffee-time&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;coffee time&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; app that connects you with another colleague every Saturday via email, just so that you can catch up with them over a warm beverage. We also have a Friday Zoom meetup where we wind down ahead of the weekend. We&amp;rsquo;re trialing &lt;a href=&#34;https://donut.ai&#34;&gt;Donut&lt;/a&gt; for more of a group coffee-time thing, and that&amp;rsquo;s been fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These meetups are always optional, so if you&amp;rsquo;ve got a heavy week, no one will make you feel bad about skipping them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-happens-if-you-spend-a-week-stuck-on-a-problem&#34;&gt;What happens if you spend a week stuck on a problem?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s rare that this will happen. We&amp;rsquo;ve got proceses in place for escalating issues that we&amp;rsquo;re especially stuck on that ropes in members of the development team, but before it even gets to that, we usually invoke one of our team values: &lt;em&gt;support engineers help one another&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-s-the-setup-like-for-meetings-with-people-in-the-office-does-it-work-well&#34;&gt;What’s the setup like for meetings with people in the office, does it work well?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first-day experience while being onboarded Fog Creek&amp;rsquo;s headquarters in NYC was a monthly Town Hall meeting. I remember feeling that it was pretty odd that everyone in the office was sitting at their own desk, in front of their own computer, headsets on, and interacting in the meeting via group videoconferencing. On the other hand, this makes it pretty inclusive for us remote folks — there&amp;rsquo;s not much in the way of sideband conversations going on when you&amp;rsquo;re all on your own webcam. So that&amp;rsquo;s pretty cool, and in practice it works well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-you-stay-productive-and-also-separate-work-life-at-home&#34;&gt;How do you stay productive and also separate work/life at home?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Productivity gets easier when you&amp;rsquo;re not exhausted by commuting, and you&amp;rsquo;ve got a dedicated area that&amp;rsquo;s set up to meet your own ideals for a productive workspace. Like Julia, I&amp;rsquo;ve found it more distracting working out of an office than working from home. I do keep a pretty clear start and end to my workday, though, and generally only set foot in the home office to do work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- link references --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Junk Drawer</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/the-junk-drawer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/the-junk-drawer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve slowly been moving over to &lt;a href=&#34;https://culturedcode.com/things/&#34;&gt;Things 3&lt;/a&gt; for task management, but more than that, I&amp;rsquo;ve been re-thinking just how my system needs to be fleshed out so that it works best for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of that move, I&amp;rsquo;ve been re-evaluating the way I think about capture. Typically, you&amp;rsquo;ve got an inbox, where you log all the incoming stuff in your life, and which you process periodically. That&amp;rsquo;s fine for the usual do-delegate-delete-defer type &lt;em&gt;tasks&lt;/em&gt;, but if I want to use Things (or whatever task management system) to capture &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ve found that I need a place for things that live somewhere between the inbox and a project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which brings me to BINQ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BINQ is a concept I heard Merlin Mann talk about on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://5by5.tv/b2w/&#34;&gt;Back To Work podcast&lt;/a&gt;, and is an acronym for &lt;strong&gt;B&lt;/strong&gt;rainstorming, &lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt;deas, &lt;strong&gt;N&lt;/strong&gt;otes, &lt;strong&gt;Q&lt;/strong&gt;uestions (or something like that).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Essentially, BINQ is a junk drawer for your thoughts. It&amp;rsquo;s a holding pen for half-baked, hare-brained ideas that need to time to fully form. Tasks in the BINQ project don&amp;rsquo;t quite yet deserve to become a project, but they really need to get out of the inbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some folks use the concept of “Someday” for these things, but in practice I’ve found that “someday” makes more sense as a temporal definition (kind of like a “pending” or &amp;ldquo;waiting&amp;rdquo; context, but important enough to be a first-class entity in the task manager). This is how Things treats “someday”: you set this as part of the &lt;em&gt;when&lt;/em&gt; for a task, not the &lt;em&gt;where&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My BINQ project lives outside of any so-called &amp;ldquo;Areas&amp;rdquo; in things — in fact, it&amp;rsquo;s the only project that isn&amp;rsquo;t part of some area of my life. A few times a week, I&amp;rsquo;ll check in and add some notes to a task that lives in there, or maybe delete something because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t make any sense to pursue further for whatever reason. Ideas for posts go into BINQ too, before a draft gets written.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a good place for checklists within tasks, too. As you start to flesh out some of these ideas, it&amp;rsquo;s handy to add checklist items to them. It then becomes pretty trivial to bring these out of BINQ quarantine and into your life using Things&amp;rsquo; convert-to-project feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, I&amp;rsquo;ve set up four headings for each of the letters in the acronym (Brainstorming, Ideas, Notes, and Questions), but I don’t love the idea of having to decide what heading a task would fall under—it injects friction into what should be a easy process. Trying to enforce too much organization on a junk drawer just means that your &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; junk drawer lives somewhere else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Too much of the pseudo-productivity silliness tries to package your life up into neat little packages, which is fine for remembering to take out the garbage, or for organizing your kitchen renovations. But sometimes, for the messy, ethereal things that come into your life, a good ol&amp;rsquo; messy junk drawer is the right place for them to live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Reference links --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spinning Plates</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/spinning-plates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/spinning-plates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I mentioned &lt;a href=&#34;http://angelo.micro.blog/2018/01/27/its-nearly-the.html&#34;&gt;the other day&lt;/a&gt; that I&amp;rsquo;m feeling a little bit discouraged with how January was going. While I started the year &lt;a href=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/post/twelve-for-2018/&#34;&gt;looking forward to taking on a list of goals&lt;/a&gt;, here we are, almost halfway into February, and I&amp;rsquo;m not really feeling like I&amp;rsquo;ve made real progress against any of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took some time to think about why this is the case, and a couple of things stand out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, the reality is that January&amp;rsquo;s been a bit of a short month. I spent a good portion of it feeling under the weather, and there’s been a lot going on, so I really didn&amp;rsquo;t have much time and energy to put into anything beyond work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bigger issue, however, is that I&amp;rsquo;ve not felt quite sure where to focus my efforts. I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;em&gt;started&lt;/em&gt; on several projects, but there are only so many things that I can move forward at once, because it requires a lot of context-switching and results in a level of progress that&amp;rsquo;s nowhere near what focused attention would generate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s in contrast to how I wrote my first iOS app. By working a little bit of overtime during the week, I was able to take Friday afternoons off over the summer, and I dedicated that time to learning and building &lt;a href=&#34;https://droppedbits.com/honeyjar/&#34;&gt;HoneyJar&lt;/a&gt;. That&amp;rsquo;s all I did with those afternoons, too — get home, launch Xcode, and work on the app, without distraction. In the sum total of maybe five or six full workdays, I learned enough about Objective-C, Xcode, iOS, CocoaPods, and iTunes Connect to ship my first app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe because I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to diving into a bunch of these projects, I haven&amp;rsquo;t really been great about getting into that focused state of flow — my attention is pulled in several different directions. So, of course, as I try to move things forward, I&amp;rsquo;m only able to make very small pushes in the general direction of progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, if you give somebody two things to work on, you should be grateful if they “starve” one task and only work on one, because they’re going to get more stuff done and finish the average task sooner. In fact, the real lesson from all this is that you should never let people work on more than one thing at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;rarr; Joel On Software, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.joelonsoftware.com/2001/02/12/human-task-switches-considered-harmful/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Human Task Switches Considered Harmful&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s like those circus acts where someone’s running from pole to pole, trying to keep the plates atop them spinning fast enough to maintain their balance, and that person unable to ever really focus on one thing because they’re too busy keeping things going in circles. I&amp;rsquo;m fighting the urge to tackle &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of my projects at the same time, but apparently not well enough. So it&amp;rsquo;s time to define what specific projects to work on, and when they&amp;rsquo;re done, move on to the next. It’s a little bit hard for me to starve one project to feed another, but it’s something I can learn to be okay with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it&amp;rsquo;s still possible to work on a couple of (carefully-chosen) goals in parallel, so long as there’s a limited overlap of domain. Maybe I only want to take on one &lt;em&gt;code&lt;/em&gt; project at a time, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean I can&amp;rsquo;t tackle a fitness project simultaneously — these are mutually exclusive in terms of their demands on my time and focus, and are probably even symbiotic (healthy mind in a healthy body, and all that jazz).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More (but only a little bit more) to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Reference Links --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twelve for 2018</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/twelve-for-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/twelve-for-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Okay, so I&amp;rsquo;m a bit late to the party, but: rather than try to create a bunch of resolutions, I’ve decided that I’d prefer to take on twelve projects this year. Why twelve? Well, largely because it breaks down to one project per month (not that I intend these to be month-long projects, it just works out that way).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In no particular order of importance, they are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn a new language:&lt;/strong&gt; My wife and I have been talking about doing this together. We don&amp;rsquo;t expect to develop fluency in a language by year end, but at the very least some conversational level where, if we were in some country, we&amp;rsquo;d be able to chat with local folks in their own language. Right now, we&amp;rsquo;re trying to decide on the language.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ship Per 2.0:&lt;/strong&gt; The last update to Per was in September of 2015. The app generally works fine, and we use it all the time when out shopping for groceries, but I have ideas for features (and am aware that the UI could &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; use an overhaul).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Run five kilometres:&lt;/strong&gt; In a row. In one session. I&amp;rsquo;ve never been an active person, and that&amp;rsquo;s going to bite me in my later years. So I&amp;rsquo;m going to tackle a couch-to-5k program and aim to be able to run a solid 5km by year end.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read one book a month:&lt;/strong&gt; I really stink at getting through my reading list. I aim to read one book a month to try to ramp that back up (and take advantage of the cool &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.manton.org/2018/01/books-on-micro-blog.html&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Books on Micro.blog&lt;/em&gt; collection&lt;/a&gt; implementation to discuss them). &lt;a href=&#34;https://micro.blog/discover/books&#34;&gt;📚&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Build one Manuscript integration:&lt;/strong&gt; Basing myself on &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/make-better-software/how-to-get-started-making-manuscript-integrations-6da236b68f98&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;m going to build a (relatively simple) &lt;a href=&#34;https://manuscript.com&#34;&gt;Manuscript&lt;/a&gt; integration that pulls App Store reviews into Manuscript.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Build a micro.blog sample app in Glitch:&lt;/strong&gt; I think that there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of value in micro.blog, but right now the barrier to entry (compared to signing up for a free Twitter account) is high enough that it won&amp;rsquo;t appeal beyond the folks who already blog (or who are able to pay US$5 per month for a hosted microblog) — a diminishingly small portion of the potential member base. Creating a free, remixable sample app in &lt;a href=&#34;https://glitch.com&#34;&gt;Glitch&lt;/a&gt; might help with accessibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pay off my credit card debt:&lt;/strong&gt; I used to be really bad with my spending. I&amp;rsquo;m significantly better now, but I&amp;rsquo;ve got some lingering credit-card debt that really needs to go.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;De-clutter my belongings:&lt;/strong&gt; I have a lot of stuff. A good chunk of that stuff is stuff that I don&amp;rsquo;t need and never use. It&amp;rsquo;s time to let go of a lot of that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Write more often:&lt;/strong&gt; I mean, I can&amp;rsquo;t really do much worse than my one-post-per-year low from last year. Technically, this is my second post for 2018, so I&amp;rsquo;m already winning this one. I aim to write about my progress on this list of projects over the course of the year, so at least I already have some topics lined up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rework my personal website and blogs:&lt;/strong&gt; My stuff is scattered across this blog, the (new) &lt;a href=&#34;https://angelo.micro.blog&#34;&gt;microblog&lt;/a&gt;, my mostly-ignored &lt;a href=&#34;http://breakbeforemake.com&#34;&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;, and my personal site. Time to think about how to bring all that together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Back-squat 225 lbs:&lt;/strong&gt; Similar to the 5K goal, I aim to focus on some strength training at the gym. I&amp;rsquo;d started on a &lt;a href=&#34;https://stronglifts.com/5x5/&#34;&gt;5&amp;times;5 lifting program&lt;/a&gt; last year and, despite some fits and starts, went from squatting just the bar to 155lbs in six months — a 240% improvement. Those are the easy percents, though, and I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to be able to get up to two plates by the end of the year, despite starting from (nearly) scratch after a 6-month hiatus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start playing piano again:&lt;/strong&gt; I haven&amp;rsquo;t seriously played piano in over 20 years. I&amp;rsquo;ve set up a keyboard in my home office to inspire me to do that again, but I&amp;rsquo;ve yet to actually start tickling the ivories, as they say. But, I mean, I did make this &lt;a href=&#34;https://noiseless-airmail.glitch.me&#34;&gt;web-audio synthesizer in Glitch&lt;/a&gt; to learn some JavaScript, so that kinda counts. Right?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here&amp;rsquo;s to 2018. I hope you make great progress on your projects and goals this year, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Reference links --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello, 2018</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/hello-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/hello-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The last thing I wrote here was a &lt;a href=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/post/2016-in-review&#34;&gt;retrospective on 2016&lt;/a&gt;, written one year and one day ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; quite a while ago. You&amp;rsquo;d think I&amp;rsquo;d have written more, given how much happened this year. Off the top of my head:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I changed jobs, and am now working with the thoughtful geniuses at &lt;a href=&#34;https://fogcreek.com&#34;&gt;Fog Creek&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I got pretty serious about personal fitness, making great progress, right up until&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;I severed a tendon in my left pinky, which left me in a splint for most of the summer after &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3293389/&#34;&gt;surgery to reattach it&lt;/a&gt; (occupational and physical therapy are still ongoing, six months later)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;we lost our wonderful fluffy companion of 15 years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from the fitness bit, none of these were events that I expected or planned for. One thing I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect, however, is how much all of this upheaval would leave me wanting to withdraw from, well, everything. I guess it&amp;rsquo;s easiest to drop the stuff that doesn&amp;rsquo;t pay the rent, and once you start doing that, you risk kicking off a downward spiral &amp;mdash; one that catches you by surprise one day, when you wake up and realize you&amp;rsquo;re fed up of not feeling like you&amp;rsquo;re doing anything that you used to enjoy anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I&amp;rsquo;m going to work on getting back into a rhythm of Getting Things Done. I&amp;rsquo;m starting by setting aside protected time this week to read, to think, and to make some progress on projects (first up: I&amp;rsquo;d &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; like to update &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/ca/app/per-shop-smart-save-money/id922693504?mt=8&amp;amp;uo=4&#34;&gt;Per&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More tk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Links to references --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twenty-sixteen, reviewed</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/2016-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/2016-in-review/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of the year, I &lt;a href=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-fresh-starts/&#34;&gt;wrote down some goals&lt;/a&gt; for 2016. The year has come and gone, so it&amp;rsquo;s not a bad idea to have a bit of a look at how things went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;review&#34;&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-post-something-here-every-friday&#34;&gt;1. Post something here every Friday&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did pretty well at this for a while, up until late August. But as the year wore on it felt more and more that I was writing just for the sake of checking off a repeating to-do item, rather than writing a goal in and of itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only did I feel that in the quality of what I was writing, I think this started injecting stress into my life. That, of course, is bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also found that trying to get some words up on screen every week took time away from working on some of the projects (writing or otherwise) that I really wanted to work on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to continue with a less-frequent schedule, putting up a minimum of one article a month. I&amp;rsquo;m also going to try posting to &lt;a href=&#34;http://breakbeforemake.com&#34;&gt;Break Before Make&lt;/a&gt; more often&amp;mdash;it&amp;rsquo;s been sorely neglected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-post-to-a-journal-at-least-once-every-day&#34;&gt;2. Post to a journal at least once every day&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I discussed this &lt;a href=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/post/a-six-month-update/&#34;&gt;six months ago&lt;/a&gt;. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll try a written journal, just because I like working on my penmanship, but honestly, it felt like something taken on because someone said it was a good idea, rather than because I found that it worked for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-make-real-progress-towards-my-mac-app&#34;&gt;3. Make real progress towards my Mac app&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I founded a company five years ago with the intention of releasing this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I&amp;rsquo;ve made no real inroads in the actual &lt;em&gt;coding&lt;/em&gt;, I have made a pretty important decision regarding the focus of the app. I think this pivot will help more people, so I&amp;rsquo;ve fleshed out a bit of a roadmap for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m making 2017 the year it finally sees the light of day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-contribute-to-open-source-projects&#34;&gt;4. Contribute to open-source projects&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not much here. I did &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sxg/ForecastIO/pull/24&#34;&gt;help update a library for Swift 3&lt;/a&gt; but that wasn&amp;rsquo;t really much of a contribution, I don&amp;rsquo;t think&amp;mdash;it was mainly more of a &amp;ldquo;fix what the Xcode migration assistant broke&amp;rdquo; kind of fix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also &lt;a href=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/tags/tghr/&#34;&gt;open-sourced my first iOS app&lt;/a&gt;, but haven&amp;rsquo;t really done much with that, either. It&amp;rsquo;s still more-or-less in burning-dumpster-fire state, which is to say, it &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; looks like a first iOS app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-get-in-better-shape&#34;&gt;5. Get in better shape&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did pretty well at running at least a couple of times a week between end of March and mid-October. Once the snow&amp;mdash;or worse, freezing rain&amp;mdash;started coming down, however, that trend kind of tapered off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I miss it, so I&amp;rsquo;ve registered at a gym with an indoor track and a pool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;onwards-and-upwards&#34;&gt;Onwards and upwards&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any day is a good day to make changes, because we live &lt;a href=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/post/flux/&#34;&gt;in a state of flux&lt;/a&gt;. So, despite missing marks and/or changing course over the last year, I&amp;rsquo;m still going to set some goals for the next year:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;goal-health&#34;&gt;Goal: &lt;em&gt;Health&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I said, I&amp;rsquo;m registering at a gym down the street from where I live, where I can do both strength and cardiovascular training. I&amp;rsquo;m not getting any younger, and holy crap am I feeling it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typically, when I start getting more physically active, everything else falls into place: sleeping longer, eating better, making better decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Citius&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Altius&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Fortius&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;goal-wealth&#34;&gt;Goal: &lt;em&gt;Wealth&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href=&#34;http://appstore.com/droppedbits?at=11ln59&amp;amp;ct=mbb&#34;&gt;iOS apps&lt;/a&gt;, despite their neglected state, are about helping people make smarter decisions about their money. My Mac app has the same goal, albeit a bit more involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way: as they haven&amp;rsquo;t been updated in a while, I&amp;rsquo;ve made the iOS apps free. Give them a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;goal-self-mastery&#34;&gt;Goal: &lt;em&gt;Self-mastery&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a good chunk of my writing, I tend to explore themes related to &lt;em&gt;getting better&lt;/em&gt;. Generally, if I&amp;rsquo;m writing about it, it&amp;rsquo;s because it&amp;rsquo;s something that I struggle with, or that I&amp;rsquo;m trying to improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than forcing that with weekly posts, I intend on posting longer-form, better-cited articles, at least once a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s to the next 365 days. I truly hope they&amp;rsquo;re full of love, laughter, and health for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One decision</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/one-decision/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/one-decision/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;As I write this, I&amp;rsquo;m sitting at a Starbucks in a mall, two days before Christmas. I&amp;rsquo;m sipping a large black coffee distractedly, watching folks noodle on by, caught up in whatever last few errands they may need to run before hosting or visiting friends and family for the holidays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mall&amp;rsquo;s background music is calm, barely-audible, and shoppers don&amp;rsquo;t seem particularly stressed out, or rushed, or frustrated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s possible that I&amp;rsquo;m projecting my mood on this scene, too. I don&amp;rsquo;t know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has been, for me, one of the least-stressful run-ups to the holidays ever. Part of that comes from the fact that our trips to see family are nicely spaced out this year, and part of it comes from the fact that I&amp;rsquo;ve been preparing for this since Christmas of last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our flat has been perfumed with the scent of Fraser fir for weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve purchased all of my gifts, which I&amp;rsquo;ll be wrapping this evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Christmas budget still has plenty of padding for any unexpected, last-minute purchases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing all your affairs are in order casts a lovely, warm glow on what can otherwise become a very hectic and chaotic time of year. Yeah, we missed the deadline for sending out Christmas cards—something we keep saying we want to do, but aren&amp;rsquo;t great about getting done—but otherwise, everything&amp;rsquo;s done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything&amp;rsquo;s done because I made one decision during the holidays last year: make Christmas this year better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;wishful-thinking-considered-harmful&#34;&gt;Wishful thinking considered harmful&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to feel that, hey, whatever, the Universe no doubt unfolds as it&amp;rsquo;s supposed to, and hopefully that means tomorrow will work out better than today did. I mean, I understood that my actions played &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; role in how that would play out, but, that said, there was always this feeling that things would work themselves out, because, well, &lt;em&gt;they&amp;rsquo;d always somehow worked themselves out&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is, until they didn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wishful thinking isn&amp;rsquo;t just optimism. It&amp;rsquo;s closing your eyes and hoping something works when you have no reasonable basis for thinking it will. Wishful thinking at the beginning of a project leads to big blowups at the end of a project. It undermines meaningful planning and may be at the root of more software problems than all other causes combined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; &lt;cite&gt;Steve McConnell&lt;/cite&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stevemcconnell.com/rdenum.htm&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Classic Mistakes Enumerated&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr McConnell wrote this with software development projects in mind, but it&amp;rsquo;s pretty broadly applicable to almost anything. Like post-secondary education. I did extremely well with little effort in high school, so I just expected that to continue through college.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That didn&amp;rsquo;t happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, I got pretty well acquainted with a concept called &amp;ldquo;Academic Probation&amp;rdquo;, a set of policies and procedures designed around the concept of &lt;em&gt;Getting Your Shit Together&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of actually recognizing that each week was going worse than the last, and taking some kind of corrective action, I kept shrugging it off and convincing myself that it&amp;rsquo;d all work out. I figured I&amp;rsquo;d ace the final, or do great on the term project, or whatever. Procrastination, anxiety, burnout, whatever the reason, I didn&amp;rsquo;t do anything to stop the downward spiral—I just fantasized about having degrees conferred and being offered great jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think life-improvement gurus call this technique &amp;ldquo;goal visualization&amp;rdquo;, but it turns out that it&amp;rsquo;s not super effective without effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;judge-jury-and-executor&#34;&gt;Judge, jury, and executor&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making a decision means consciously choosing what takes priority in your life, and this also means choosing what &lt;em&gt;doesn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; take priority in your life. This has, historically, been the hard part for me; your time-management system can&amp;rsquo;t manage to tack an extra couple of hours onto your day, so if you decide that project A lives, then you&amp;rsquo;re by necessity deciding that projects B, C, and maybe even D must &lt;em&gt;die&lt;/em&gt;. If you decide that you need to buy a new car, you&amp;rsquo;re by necessity deciding that you &lt;em&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t get to retire&lt;/em&gt; for at least another year or two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s only when I realized this that I started becoming the (relatively-more-) effective and productive person I am today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much like the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2015/05/an-economist-reads-marie-kondo/392921/&#34;&gt;KonMari method of tidying&lt;/a&gt;, you need a very specific mindset when you&amp;rsquo;re going through your tasks, or your budget, or your goals, or whatever. Except the decision to keep or drop a thing isn&amp;rsquo;t going to be based on whether it brings you joy; it&amp;rsquo;s going to be based on the fact that it requires sacrificing something. Something that you once sacrificed another thing for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which, in turn, you sacrificed something else for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;looking-out-the-top-of-the-windshield&#34;&gt;Looking out the top of the windshield&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally, as people, we&amp;rsquo;re not particularly good at forethought. Mired in the day-to-day, we neglect the future until it becomes a mistake-ridden past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, fixing this isn&amp;rsquo;t especially hard—it just takes a certain amount of mindfulness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was learning how to drive, one of the best pieces of advice that I got was to pick a point about three-quarters up the windshield in front of me, and try to look above that point at least as often as I look below it. The point of this exercise was to train yourself to look as far down the road as possible, as often as possible, without ignoring what&amp;rsquo;s going on right in front of you. In doing so, you see hazards and congestions and what-have-you long before they became an unavoidable problem. You can then make small, gentle course corrections right away, smoothly merging into another lane to avoid a pothole two blocks away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Man, I wish I&amp;rsquo;d been able to grok the life lesson in that right away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long-term goals influence short-term goals. The farther out you plan, the easier it is to make decisions in the near-term about what gets to stay in your life, and what has to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, you&amp;rsquo;re really only answering a single question: does this make [tomorrow / next week / next month / next year] better?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the to-do lists and GTD methodologies in the world aren&amp;rsquo;t going to help you, until you can make that one decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/images/one-decision/ofqe-cards.png&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;quot;Omnifocus Quick-Entry window&amp;quot;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yeah, we&amp;rsquo;ll be sending out Christmas cards next year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On criticism</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-criticism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-criticism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I see a lot of digital ink spilled on how some particular thing is&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;broken&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;taking a quality nose-dive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;stupid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;irrelevant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;amp;cet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it&amp;rsquo;s good to be critical. With a bit of healthy skepticism, we avoid the reality-distortion fields that turn rational-minded folks into zealots. Nothing is so perfect that it can&amp;rsquo;t be improved, and I get that this is the place that a lot of these &lt;em&gt;thinkpieces&lt;/em&gt; come from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the thing is, communication should serve some purpose. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily have to be some call to action, but it &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt;, at the very least, let the audience answer one simple question:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What am I to do with this information?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, if you&amp;rsquo;re telling me how crappy something is, what&amp;rsquo;s the point? Are you proposing some solution?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or are you just complaining?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s okay if you are. We&amp;rsquo;re human and we have &lt;em&gt;feelings&lt;/em&gt; about things. Talking about those feelings can help you find common ground with others who feel ways about stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But let&amp;rsquo;s abstain from calling it criticism. Constructive criticism moves a thing forward; it offers the receiver something to work with. This is key: it generates goodwill, and it helps make things better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And—given that the world is made up of things—constructive criticism makes the world a slightly better place, by extension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is nice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Per</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/per-schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/per-schedule/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t posted here in a little while, thus &lt;a href=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-streaks/&#34;&gt;breaking the streak&lt;/a&gt; that I was intending to maintain. I don&amp;rsquo;t feel too bad about this, because I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on other stuff in the meanwhile, but it&amp;rsquo;s nice to be writing again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specifically, in light of the coming &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/support/app-store-improvements/&#34;&gt;App Store purge&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a big update to &lt;a href=&#34;http://droppedbits.com/per&#34;&gt;Per&lt;/a&gt;. While I&amp;rsquo;m not especially concerned that Per, in its current form, is at risk of being culled, it &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; been a long time since it was updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For one, I&amp;rsquo;m dropping support for anything prior to iOS 10. Per has a pretty tiny user base&amp;mdash;maybe a couple hundred downloads&amp;mdash;and I don&amp;rsquo;t see much in the way of daily active users&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but for such a tiny user base, I can&amp;rsquo;t justify putting effort into supporting iOS 8 and 9.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second on the list is a pretty hefty redesign. I fully admit that Per is… kinda homely-looking. There are some interactions that I&amp;rsquo;m planning on (and have started experimenting with) for 2.0, and while it&amp;rsquo;s slow going, I like what I see so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also thinking about taking advantage of some new input methods, but I don&amp;rsquo;t know yet how well that will work. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to tip my hand just yet because those may not be technically feasible, but it&amp;rsquo;s got me pretty interested in seeing what can be done&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third on the list is the business model for Per.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Per brings in pretty much zero revenue. Most of the downloads came from a period of time when I made my apps free for a week, whereas the normally-paid (at USD$1.99) version has seen only a handful of downloads at most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that I haven&amp;rsquo;t marketed Per at all, save for a couple of tweets and blog posts, so this isn&amp;rsquo;t unexpected. But I think it&amp;rsquo;s time to change that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the way the App Store economy works, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty clear that charging up-front is a barrier to getting your app downloaded. This is no secret, so some business model that includes free downloads makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One option is to make Per free, with an in-app purchase (IAP) to unlock advanced features, like the unit conversion and  in-field math operations it already features, and the new input methods mentioned. This means zero revenue unless people want these features. How desirable are they in a relatively simple utility app like Per?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another option is to make Per free, but ad-supported. Thing is, I personally don&amp;rsquo;t like the aesthetic that ads introduce in an app&amp;rsquo;s interface and experience, and I know I&amp;rsquo;m not the only one. So there would definitely have to be an IAP to remove ads. I have a couple of ideas on where and when I&amp;rsquo;d show an ad, so they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; annoying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both cases mean that current paying users would experience either reduced functionality, or an ad-filled experience. That sucks, so yet &lt;em&gt;another&lt;/em&gt; option would be to create a new SKU. Folks that have the original version of Per get a fully-featured and ad-free upgrade, and new users could opt to pay for this version outright, whereas the other version of the app would implement one of the above options, but would list for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s a fair bit of extra administrative work for me, and confusing for both old and new users, so I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ll do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could also leave Per as-is and create a new SKU for Per 2. No further updates for the old app, but then that also probably means it&amp;rsquo;ll eventually be culled from the App Store anyhow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that something like 3 users have actually &lt;em&gt;paid&lt;/em&gt; for Per (thanks!), I think that I&amp;rsquo;ll skip the two-SKU options altogether, because they&amp;rsquo;re administrative headaches. This means that Per 2 will be a free upgrade, but will either be removing some features or including ads (sorry!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe there&amp;rsquo;s a way to check whether a user paid for an app or not, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure. &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:contact@angelostavrow.com&#34;&gt;Let me know&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned, I know that Per is really just a simple utility app, but it&amp;rsquo;s something that my wife and I use pretty much every time we shop for groceries. It&amp;rsquo;s certainly &lt;em&gt;useful&lt;/em&gt;, but I also want it to be &lt;em&gt;great&lt;/em&gt;. That not only means redesigns and refactoring, but it also means getting it in the hands of as many people as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More tk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;footnote&#34; id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;I know that this could be because most people disable sharing this data when they set up their phone.&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; title=&#34;return to article&#34;&gt; ↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;footnote&#34; id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Seems to me that, for some developers, adding a new feature to an older app has less to do with a revenue bump than it does the excitement of tackling a new problem. That&#39;s how I feel, anyhow.&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; title=&#34;return to article&#34;&gt; ↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPhone Unplugged</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/iphone-unplugged/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/iphone-unplugged/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s widely expected that the next iPhone will be announced tomorrow during the scheduled Apple Event. For months now, the rumour mill has been telling us that the most controversial change Apply is making to its flagship product is the removal of the headphone jack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, it seems like a certainty. The headphone jack in its current form has existed for decades, but Apple is notorious for advancing physical I/O past its status quo: witness the current MacBook with its single USB-C port, and recall the Lightning and 30-pin connectors on iOS devices, the adoption of Thunderbolt on current Macs, the even introduction of USB on the original iMac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time Apple introduces a new port standard, or drops an old one, the ecosystem adapts. Because iPhones didn&amp;rsquo;t use micro-USB connections, pundits complained that it&amp;rsquo;d be nigh-impossible to charge and sync your phone if the included cable got lost or damaged. Fast forward only a few years after the introduction of the iPhone, and 30-pin cables can be found nearly anywhere that has even the most modest of electronics departments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the headphone port has always been around. There&amp;rsquo;s some expectation of Lightning-connected earbuds, which poses a charge-while-listening dilemma, and there will almost certainly be Lightning-to-3.5mm adapters&amp;mdash;if not from Apple, then definitely from third parties. But adapters add bulk and are easily lost. Which leads to the next option: Bluetooth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wireless options have been available for a long time, but they&amp;rsquo;ve never really been particularly well-received: they&amp;rsquo;re expensive, the sound quality isn&amp;rsquo;t great, &amp;amp;cet. The real problem, as I see it, is that a wireless device is an active device by necessity. It has to power its own wireless radios, and in this case also power the audio drivers. That means batteries. That means battery life (hours of use per charge), and battery lifespan (number of charges per battery).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What all this means for iPhone 7 users is not forgetting to charge things, but also not charging things too often. It means not losing adapters. It means having to plan ahead to ensure you don&amp;rsquo;t need to charge your phone while listening to music. It means that there&amp;rsquo;s now an additional bit of cognitive load on you, which is never good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This&lt;/em&gt; is my main problem with some of these changes. I want new technologies to &lt;em&gt;relieve me&lt;/em&gt; of stuff to think about, not &lt;em&gt;add&lt;/em&gt; more busywork and more administrative B.S. to keep on top of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know this is a barely a blip in the grand scheme of things&amp;mdash;heck, it&amp;rsquo;s only a headphone port&amp;mdash;but it nicely captures The Problem With Technology As I See It. Moving the state of the art forward should always be in the service of freeing us to do more important things. And I don&amp;rsquo;t think changes like this necessarily do so.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Split iPhone</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/split-iphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/split-iphone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/images/2016-08-26/split-iphone.png&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I noticed this earlier in the year, but my iPhone is coming apart at the seams near the volume buttons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, I figured I&amp;rsquo;d managed to bend the phone, but upon closer inspection, both the back of the case and the screen are bulging outward&amp;mdash;which is not the failure mode you&amp;rsquo;d expect for a bent phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gap at the seam is nearly 2mm, such that light from the screen leaks, but it&amp;rsquo;s nowhere near as bad as I&amp;rsquo;ve seen doing an image search. The screen doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be cracking, though I can see weird artifacts in the backlighting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;I thought my iPhone was bent, but both the back and the front bulge outward, with no cracking of the display. Bloated battery, maybe?&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Angelo Stavrow (@AngeloStavrow) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AngeloStavrow/status/768490399249739776&#34;&gt;August 24, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most signs point to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://talestoldfromtheroad.com/2014/08/14/battery-can-swell-and-crack-iphone-screen/&#34;&gt;bloated battery&lt;/a&gt; being the culprit. This doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound like a safe state for a plastic baggie full of acid and electrons, so off to the Genius Bar we go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strike&gt;More tk.&lt;/strike&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One look at the phone and the Genius confirmed the diagnosis. Normally, in the case of a bloated battery, they won&amp;rsquo;t bother with replacing the battery, in case it&amp;rsquo;s started leaking and caused damage to other internal components&amp;mdash;they give you a new phone and your old device gets sent off to &lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/AYshVbcEmUc&#34;&gt;Liam&lt;/a&gt; for disassembly and recycling. If you&amp;rsquo;re still covered by AppleCare, the exchange is free, but if not, you only pay for a replacement battery, not a replacement phone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light writing</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/light-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/light-writing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/images/2016-08-19/olympus-pen.jpg&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Literally &lt;em&gt;writing with light&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;photography&lt;/em&gt;, as it&amp;rsquo;s more commonly known.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to think that I loved photography. I think I still do, I just&amp;hellip; never really do it anymore. At one point I had a whole mess of expensive camera gear, with the fancy full-frame digital SLR and red-ring&amp;rsquo;d lenses. And the fast primes&amp;mdash;oh, I loved those. Studio strobes? Yup. Speedlights? Several. Fifty pounds of camera gear that stayed home because, I convinced myself, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be arsed to carry fifty pounds of camera gear around with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless there was some kind of cool reason to. I helped shoot a wedding and did a men&amp;rsquo;s fashion shoot. Several portraits, too. But mostly, the gear stayed at home, collecting dust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean, fifty pounds. I&amp;rsquo;m a relatively fit person, but come on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I sold it all and downsized to a small micro-four-thirds setup. A kit zoom, a couple of fast primes, and a speedlight. Fifty pounds traded for five and a bucketful of cash. &lt;em&gt;Now&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;rsquo;d start taking more photos. &lt;em&gt;Obviously&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t, of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thing is, I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; enjoy photography. Crafting an image is immensely satisfying. Capturing a great moment is fun. But I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten lazy about it, because the best camera is the one that&amp;rsquo;s with you, and by gum the camera on my iPhone is pretty fantastic, all things considered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it&amp;rsquo;s not the same. And while I don&amp;rsquo;t want to become fifty-pound camera-guy again, I do think I&amp;rsquo;ll take a cue from &lt;a href=&#34;https://ashfurrow.com/blog/photography-retrospective/&#34;&gt;Ash Furrow&lt;/a&gt; and start walking around with my little PEN day-to-day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean, look how &lt;em&gt;pretty&lt;/em&gt; it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course, in true keeping-myself-honest fashion, I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to do a photo post every so often. Maybe once a month. Maybe some old photos, maybe some new photos, maybe a couple of words too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More &amp;mdash;as always&amp;mdash; tk. 📸&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swift, UnitTemperature, And Humidex</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/swift-unittemperature-and-humidex/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/swift-unittemperature-and-humidex/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, I &lt;a href=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/post/how-about-that-heat/&#34;&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; about weather apps that use &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.forecast.io&#34;&gt;the Dark Sky forecast API&lt;/a&gt; for weather data lacking the Canadian &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Humidex&#34;&gt;humidex&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those that do tend to be riddled with ads and all kinds of content that, well, I don&amp;rsquo;t care about. And naturally, I started thinking about how I use weather apps. All I really want from my is a couple of things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Current conditions, including humidex/ windchill values;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forecast conditions with highs and lows for today and tomorrow, again including humidex and windchill;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Probability of precipitation for the next hour, with alerts of impending rain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting the actual forecast along with alerts is a solved problem, thanks to Forecast.io. Doing conversion and such between different units is also a solved problem, thanks to the new &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/reference/foundation/nsmeasurement&#34;&gt;Measurement&lt;/a&gt; class in Cocoa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&#34;http://yannickloriot.com/2016/06/measurements-and-units-ios/&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a great starter post on Meaurement&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what would, say, a basic &lt;code&gt;CurrentConditions&lt;/code&gt; object look like in my ideal app? Probably something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;import Foundation

struct CurrentConditions {
    var conditions: String
    var airTemperature: Measurement&amp;lt;UnitTemperature&amp;gt;
    var dewpoint: Measurement&amp;lt;UnitTemperature&amp;gt;
    
    var humidex: Measurement&amp;lt;UnitTemperature&amp;gt; {
        return Measurement(value: airTemperature.converted(to: UnitTemperature.celsius).value + 0.5555 * ((6.11 * exp(5417.7530 * ((1/273.16) - (1/dewpoint.converted(to: UnitTemperature.kelvin).value)))) - 10), unit: UnitTemperature.celsius)
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We initialize this strict with some descriptive weather conditions (e.g., &amp;ldquo;cloudy&amp;rdquo;), and values for the air (i.e., actual) temperature and dewpoint. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t really matter what units we use when we pass the values in, because the calculated property &lt;code&gt;humidex&lt;/code&gt; will convert them to Celsius and Kelvin respectively, before returning a value in Celsius.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then you can simply add a switch in your weather app&amp;rsquo;s settings asking the user if they prefer apparent temperature be calculated according to heat index or humidex.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How about that heat?</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/how-about-that-heat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/how-about-that-heat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;In other news, I’m totally ready for this sweltering summer to be over.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Angelo Stavrow (@AngeloStavrow) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AngeloStavrow/status/761251463213441025&#34;&gt;August 4, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t deal well with heat brought on by humidity. Which makes a Montreal summer pretty tough to deal with. Temperatures will routinely go over 30&amp;deg;C, but when combined with high humidity, it&amp;rsquo;ll feel even hotter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like, three-showers-a-day-ain&amp;rsquo;t-enough hot. Grimy, unpleasant, swampy hot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And most weather apps out there don&amp;rsquo;t get it. Sure, they have a &amp;ldquo;feels like&amp;rdquo; temperature that compensates for some of it, but it never feels quite right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To really understand how it works, you need a weather app made by Canadians, for Canadians. Because Canadians use a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Humidex&#34;&gt;humidex&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/images/2016-08-05/feels-like.png&#34; alt=&#34;Feels like&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humidex distinguishes itself from the US &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heat_index&#34;&gt;heat index&lt;/a&gt; in that it&amp;rsquo;s proportional to the dew point, not relative humidity. And generally, it&amp;rsquo;s significantly higher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen days where the &amp;ldquo;actual&amp;rdquo; temperature (i.e., air temperature) is in the high twenties, but the &amp;ldquo;feels like&amp;rdquo; humidex is mid-thirties. That&amp;rsquo;s a huge difference&amp;mdash;what&amp;rsquo;s comfortable to wear at one temperature may not be at the other. Or worse: if you&amp;rsquo;re living with some medical conditions, the decision to leave the comfort of air conditioning may even be fatal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A cursory look at weather apps (I&amp;rsquo;ve used many) shows that most use &lt;a href=&#34;https://forecast.io&#34;&gt;Forecast.io&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s API. It&amp;rsquo;s a great data source, especially for its hyper-local precipitation forecasts. But&amp;mdash;and this of course makes sense, given market sizes&amp;mdash;it doesn&amp;rsquo;t use Canadian humidex calculations to derive the apparent temperature, so I never feel like I can trust these apps for forecast highs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All I really want from a weather app is accurate alerts for incoming precipitation, and (humidex-corrected) forecast highs for the day. I&amp;rsquo;ve keep telling myself that I don&amp;rsquo;t want to take on new projects, but having to switch between a couple of apps every day is kind of a pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🤔&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Give-A-💩 Manifesto</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/give-a-smiling-poop-manifesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/give-a-smiling-poop-manifesto/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WHEREAS IT IS AGREED THAT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There exist &lt;strong&gt;THINGS&lt;/strong&gt; which one &lt;strong&gt;MUST DO&lt;/strong&gt;; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There exist &lt;strong&gt;THINGS&lt;/strong&gt; which one &lt;strong&gt;WOULD ENJOY DOING&lt;/strong&gt;; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The above-listed &lt;strong&gt;THINGS&lt;/strong&gt; may be &lt;strong&gt;MUTUALLY EXCLUSIVE&lt;/strong&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IT IS RESOLVED THAT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where a &lt;strong&gt;THING&lt;/strong&gt; is &lt;strong&gt;ENJOYED&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;MUST BE DONE&lt;/strong&gt;, one shall &lt;strong&gt;REVEL&lt;/strong&gt; for one can easily give a 💩 about it; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where a &lt;strong&gt;THING&lt;/strong&gt; is &lt;strong&gt;ENJOYED&lt;/strong&gt; but whose execution is &lt;strong&gt;NOT REQUIRED&lt;/strong&gt;, one shall strive to &lt;strong&gt;MAKE THE TIME&lt;/strong&gt; for it, for it is good to do things one gives a 💩 about; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where a &lt;strong&gt;THING&lt;/strong&gt; is &lt;strong&gt;NOT ENJOYABLE&lt;/strong&gt; but &lt;strong&gt;MUST BE DONE&lt;/strong&gt;, one shall &lt;a href=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/post/or-just-strive-to-be-the-best/&#34;&gt;give a 💩 about executing the &lt;strong&gt;THING&lt;/strong&gt; with &lt;strong&gt;CARE AND ATTENTION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where a &lt;strong&gt;THING&lt;/strong&gt; is &lt;strong&gt;NOT ENJOYABLE&lt;/strong&gt; and is &lt;strong&gt;NOT REQUIRED&lt;/strong&gt;, one shall strive to &lt;strong&gt;ELIMINATE IT&lt;/strong&gt; from the list of things one invites into their lives, for one should strive to fill their lives with things one gives a 💩 about.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AND THE MANIFESTO IS THUS RELEASED FOR APPLICATION&lt;/strong&gt; on this day in the presence of these &lt;strong&gt;WITNESSES&lt;/strong&gt;, the &lt;strong&gt;READERS&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wallet-based business cards</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/wallet-based-business-cards/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/wallet-based-business-cards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Fun little morning project. 📇📲&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;(Barcode is blurred because I’m not quite done yet. 🙃) &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/4eXh5NdTCP&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/4eXh5NdTCP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Angelo Stavrow (@AngeloStavrow) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AngeloStavrow/status/731444850118279168&#34;&gt;May 14, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of months ago I played a little bit with PassKit and Wallet after finding &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.atomicbird.com/blog/passbook-card-details&#34;&gt;this little tutorial&lt;/a&gt; on adding a business card to Passbook (now named Wallet).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Wallet pass is pretty easy to create&amp;mdash;just fill some metadata into a JSON file, create a Pass Type ID certificate in your Apple Developer account, and then run a signing utility. The whole process is pretty well described, step-by-step, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.myuiviews.com/2014/06/01/step-by-step-create-a-passbook-business-card.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, so I won&amp;rsquo;t re-iterate, but here are a couple of little perils and pitfalls to watch out for:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;To run &lt;code&gt;signpass&lt;/code&gt;, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/services-account/download?path=/iOS/Wallet_Support_Materials/WalletCompanionFiles.zip&#34;&gt;download the Xcode project&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/library/prerelease/content/documentation/UserExperience/Conceptual/PassKit_PG/&#34;&gt;Wallet Developer Guide&lt;/a&gt;. Unzip the download and open &lt;strong&gt;signpass.xcodeproj&lt;/strong&gt; in the &lt;strong&gt;signpass&lt;/strong&gt; folder. Build it, right-click on the executable in the &lt;strong&gt;Products&lt;/strong&gt; folder in Xcode&amp;rsquo;s file navigator, and select &amp;ldquo;Show in Finder&amp;rdquo;; drag and drop it into your Documents folder.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After you run &lt;code&gt;signpass&lt;/code&gt; from the Terminal, run &lt;code&gt;open PassName.pkpass&lt;/code&gt; and it&amp;rsquo;ll open in a Preview QuickLook window. From here, you can click on the &amp;ldquo;Add to Wallet&amp;rdquo; button and it&amp;rsquo;ll go up to iCloud and download to your iOS devices, without having to upload it to a server.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/images/2016-07-22/pkpass-open-front.png&#34; alt=&#34;Preview QuickLook&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the pass doesn&amp;rsquo;t show up in your iOS device, there&amp;rsquo;s probably a typo in your JSON. Look for extra/missing commas, parentheses, square brackets, &amp;amp;cet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can double-check by launching Xcode&amp;rsquo;s Simulator, launching the Wallet app, and dragging and dropping your .pkpass file from the Finder into your Simulator Wallet. If everything checks out, it&amp;rsquo;ll ask if you want to add it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/images/2016-07-22/add-to-simulator.png&#34; alt=&#34;Simulator add pass&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re uploading it to S3, make sure you set the Content-Type to &lt;code&gt;application/vnd.apple.pkpass&lt;/code&gt;. Normally, this is a dropdown, but you can also just type whatever you want in there and S3 will accept it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/images/2016-07-22/set-content-type.png&#34; alt=&#34;S3 Content-Type&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now you have a fancy electronic business card that other iPhone users can scan and download. Have fun!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using XCTAssertThrowsError in your Swift tests</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/using-xctassertthrowserror-in-your-swift-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/using-xctassertthrowserror-in-your-swift-tests/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a new kid on the XCTest block, and its name is &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/reference/xctest/1500795-xctassertthrowserror&#34;&gt;XCTAssertThrowsError&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to find much on its usage aside from its original discussion on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://lists.swift.org/pipermail/swift-evolution/Week-of-Mon-20160104/006091.html&#34;&gt;swift-evolution mailing list&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/36190161/xctassertthrowserror-strange-behavior-with-custom-errorhandler&#34;&gt;Stack Overflow question&lt;/a&gt;, so here&amp;rsquo;s a little bit of a discussion on how I&amp;rsquo;m using it in a new project of mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Swift introduced some pretty neat error handling in 2.0, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.natashatherobot.com/swift-2-error-handling/&#34;&gt;Natasha the Robot provided a nice guide&lt;/a&gt; on how to throw an error in your code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, as a contrived example, let&amp;rsquo;s say you have a class called &lt;code&gt;AccountManager&lt;/code&gt; that manages a set of &lt;code&gt;Account&lt;/code&gt; objects:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;enum ListError: ErrorType {
    case AccountAlreadyExistsInList
    case AccountDoesNotExistInList
}

class AccountManager {
    var accountList = Set&amp;lt;Account&amp;gt;()    // Account conforms to Hashable, Equatable. I promise.

    func add(_ account: Account) throws {
        if (accountList.contains(account)) {
            throw ListError.AccountAlreadyExistsInList
        }
        else {
            accountList.insert(account)
        }
    }

    func remove(_ account: Account) throws {
        if (accountList.contains(account)) {
            accountList.remove(account)
        }
        else {
            throw ListError.AccountDoesNotExistInList
        }
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Note that in Swift 3, &lt;code&gt;ErrorType&lt;/code&gt; has been renamed to &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/reference/swift/errorprotocol&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ErrorProtocol&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of things to know about the &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/reference/swift/set&#34;&gt;Set&lt;/a&gt; type:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No duplicates can be added, a Set is silent when you try to add an element that it already contains.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unless you&amp;rsquo;re checking its return type, Set is also silent when you try to remove an element that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t contain&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this protects the integrity of the Set, it could be a bit frustrating for consumers of the &lt;code&gt;AccountManager&lt;/code&gt; class, because there&amp;rsquo;s no way to surface what&amp;rsquo;s going on when we try to add a duplicate or remove a non-existent element. So, we throw!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specifically, what we&amp;rsquo;re doing in the &lt;code&gt;AccountManager&lt;/code&gt; class is checking to see if the &lt;code&gt;Account&lt;/code&gt; argument we&amp;rsquo;re passing to the &lt;code&gt;add(account:)&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;remove(account:)&lt;/code&gt; functions already exists in the &lt;code&gt;accountList&lt;/code&gt; Set, and handling the result appropriately:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If we&amp;rsquo;re trying to &lt;code&gt;remove&lt;/code&gt; an &lt;code&gt;Account&lt;/code&gt; from the &lt;code&gt;accountList&lt;/code&gt; and it exists, go ahead and do so. If it doesn&amp;rsquo;t, throw &lt;code&gt;ListError.AccountDoesNotExistInList&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If we&amp;rsquo;re trying to &lt;code&gt;add&lt;/code&gt; an &lt;code&gt;Account&lt;/code&gt; to the &lt;code&gt;accountList&lt;/code&gt; and it exists, throw &lt;code&gt;ListError.AccountAlreadyExistsInList&lt;/code&gt;. If it doesn&amp;rsquo;t, go ahead and add it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course, in our unit tests, we want to check that these errors are thrown properly. Enter &lt;code&gt;XCTAssertThrowsError&lt;/code&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;// Test that adding a duplicate account to an accountList throws an error.
func testAdd_AddingDuplicateAccount_ThrowsAccountAlreadyExistsInList() {
    let accounts = AccountManager()
    let firstAccount = Account(descriptiveName: &amp;quot;Account 1&amp;quot;, accountNumber: &amp;quot;12345AZ&amp;quot;)
    let secondAccount = Account(descriptiveName: &amp;quot;Account 1&amp;quot;, accountNumber: &amp;quot;12345AZ&amp;quot;)

    accounts.add(firstAccount)

    XCTAssertThrowsError(try accounts.add(secondAccount))
}

// Test that removing an account from an empty accountList throws an error.
func testRemove_RemovingAccountFromEmptyList_ThrowsAccountDoesNotExistInList() {
    let accounts = AccountManager()
    let firstAccount = Account(descriptiveName: &amp;quot;Account 1&amp;quot;, accountNumber: &amp;quot;12345AZ&amp;quot;)

    XCTAssertThrowsError(try accounts.remove(firstAccount))
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Run the tests and they&amp;rsquo;ll pass, because the tested expression throws an error. Cool!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a good start, but we&amp;rsquo;re only testing that &lt;em&gt;an&lt;/em&gt; error is thrown. That&amp;rsquo;s not good enough, of course, because &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; error thrown will make this test pass, but we&amp;rsquo;re looking for a &lt;em&gt;specific&lt;/em&gt; error. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a closer look at the declaration for &lt;code&gt;XCTAssertThrowsError&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;func XCTAssertThrowsError&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;(_ expression: @autoclosure () throws -&amp;gt; T,
                                _ message: @autoclosure () -&amp;gt; String = default,
                                     file: StaticString = #file,
                                     line: UInt = #line,
                             errorHandler: (error: ErrorProtocol) -&amp;gt; Void = default)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve split the signature up so that there&amp;rsquo;s just one argument per line. The description for each argument is &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/reference/xctest/1500795-xctassertthrowserror#parameters&#34;&gt;available in the  documentation&lt;/a&gt;, so I won&amp;rsquo;t repeat them here, but the important thing to note is that &lt;code&gt;XCTAssertThrowsError&lt;/code&gt; is actually a &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/library/ios/documentation/Swift/Conceptual/Swift_Programming_Language/Generics.html&#34;&gt;generic&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;code&gt;T&lt;/code&gt;. This means that in the &lt;code&gt;expression&lt;/code&gt; argument, we can add a closure that checks to see if, in fact, an error of type &lt;code&gt;T&lt;/code&gt; is being thrown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s add those checks to our two tests:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;// Test that adding a duplicate account to an accountList throws an AccountAlreadyExistsInList error.
    func testAdd_AddingDuplicateAccount_ThrowsAccountAlreadyExistsInList() {
    let accounts = AccountManager()
    let firstAccount = Account(descriptiveName: &amp;quot;Account 1&amp;quot;, accountNumber: &amp;quot;12345AZ&amp;quot;)
    let secondAccount = Account(descriptiveName: &amp;quot;Account 1&amp;quot;, accountNumber: &amp;quot;12345AZ&amp;quot;)

    accounts.add(firstAccount)

    XCTAssertThrowsError(try accounts.add(secondAccount)) { (error) -&amp;gt; Void in
        XCTAssertEqual(error as? ListError, ListError.AccountAlreadyExistsInList)
    }
}

// Test that removing an account from an empty accountList throws an AccountDoesNotExistInList error.
func testRemove_RemovingAccountFromEmptyList_ThrowsAccountDoesNotExistInList() {
    let accounts = AccountManager()
    let firstAccount = Account(descriptiveName: &amp;quot;Account 1&amp;quot;, accountNumber: &amp;quot;12345AZ&amp;quot;)

    XCTAssertThrowsError(try accounts.remove(firstAccount)) { (error) -&amp;gt; Void in
        XCTAssertEqual(error as? ListError, ListError.AccountDoesNotExistInList)
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we&amp;rsquo;re &lt;em&gt;sure&lt;/em&gt; that we&amp;rsquo;re testing that the right error is being thrown in our tests: in the closure, we call &lt;em&gt;another&lt;/em&gt; assertion, &lt;code&gt;XCTAssertEqual&lt;/code&gt;, to check that the error being thrown is the type of &lt;code&gt;ListError&lt;/code&gt; that we expect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does this mean? We no longer have to create weirdo functions that return a tuple &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;U, V&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, where &lt;code&gt;U&lt;/code&gt; is the result and &lt;code&gt;V&lt;/code&gt; is an error that you can check for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can add other arguments to your assertion, like a message or the specific file and line number if the test fails, but for now this should be enough to get you started checking your error throwing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;footnote&#34; id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Of course, you &lt;i&gt;should&lt;/i&gt; be checking the return type, and you’d see that you got back &lt;code&gt;nil&lt;/code&gt;, but like I said: this is a contrived example.&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; title=&#34;return to article&#34;&gt; ↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posting to Hugo on GitLab Pages from iOS</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/posting-to-hugo-on-gitlab-pages-from-ios/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/posting-to-hugo-on-gitlab-pages-from-ios/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In moving this blog to a static site generator, one concern was whether I&amp;rsquo;d still be able to work on and/or publish a post from my phone. I tend to do a fair bit of mobile drafting while I&amp;rsquo;m in the subway or waiting in line, and will sometimes publish content when I&amp;rsquo;m away from my computer. YOLO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a given&amp;mdash;since that&amp;rsquo;s how the site has been setup&amp;mdash;that you need a GitLab.com account, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/pages/hugo&#34;&gt;Hugo set up with GitLab CI&lt;/a&gt; to build the site and deploy it to GitLab Pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my iPhone, I have &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/ca/app/working-copy-powerful-git/id896694807?mt=8&amp;amp;uo=4&#34;&gt;Working Copy&lt;/a&gt;, which I use for git operations on the repository. It&amp;rsquo;s an excellent app, and when you pair it with &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/ca/app/editorial/id673907758?mt=8&amp;amp;uo=4&#34;&gt;Editorial&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s powerful workflow and text editing capabilities, you&amp;rsquo;ve got a great toolkit for repository management as well as writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like using issues as jumping off points for new posts (including &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/AngeloStavrow/makebeforebreak.com/issues/4&#34;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt;, so I also use &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/ca/app/git-trident-for-github-gitlab/id983962683?mt=8&#34;&gt;Git Trident&lt;/a&gt; to manage this in GitLab from my phone. Matt&amp;rsquo;s working hard on making this the best app for handling GitHub and GitLab issues on your iOS device, and I&amp;rsquo;m especially looking forward to offline access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;workflow&#34;&gt;Workflow&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post was a test for how to add content to the site from my phone, and here&amp;rsquo;s how I&amp;rsquo;m going to do it from now on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Usually (but not always), an issue tagged &lt;code&gt;post idea&lt;/code&gt; is the basis for a new post. When I&amp;rsquo;m ready to write, I assign the issue to myself and set a due date for it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I then create a new branch as &lt;code&gt;n_post_post-subject_yyyy-mm-dd&lt;/code&gt; in Working Copy, where &lt;code&gt;n&lt;/code&gt; is the issue number and &lt;code&gt;yyyy-mm-dd&lt;/code&gt; is the post date. If no issue exists, I drop the &lt;code&gt;n_&lt;/code&gt; prefix in the branch name. I try to avoid setting a title, as this can change over the course of the post. &amp;ldquo;Post subject&amp;rdquo; is already pretty well defined, since I know what I want to write about.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next, I create a new text file in Working Copy under &lt;code&gt;/content/post&lt;/code&gt;, and open it in Editorial via the share sheet to start writing. I have a &lt;a href=&#34;https://smilesoftware.com/TextExpander&#34;&gt;TextExpander&lt;/a&gt; snippet to add the TOML front matter; it&amp;rsquo;s also set as a draft, to ensure it doesn&amp;rsquo;t get published accidentally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then comes the hard part: write the post. Commit as necessary with Working Copy&amp;rsquo;s workflow for Editorial. I commit and push for a &amp;ldquo;cloud save&amp;rdquo;, or if I think I might want to continue elsewhere (i.e., on my desktop, or in a web editor&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When it&amp;rsquo;s all said and done, I set &lt;code&gt;&#39;draft = false&lt;/code&gt; in the front matter, commit and push with message &lt;code&gt;Closes #n&lt;/code&gt;, where &lt;code&gt;n&lt;/code&gt; is the issue number.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When I&amp;rsquo;m ready to publish, I launch Safari and go to GitLab.com to open a new merge request. Merging the draft branch into &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; will trigger GitLab CI; once the build passes, the post will be published. I also delete the original branch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it! The post is published. Enjoy a tasty, refreshing beverage!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote the majority of this post on my iPhone, although I&amp;rsquo;ll admit that it does feel a bit silly to tap away on a 4.7&amp;rdquo; screen when I&amp;rsquo;ve got a 24&amp;rdquo; monitor and full-size keyboard to work with. Still, for drafting and editing, it&amp;rsquo;s great, and in a pinch (or, say, on an iPad with an external keyboard), you can keep your blog running from your iOS device without issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;footnote&#34; id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Web editor, you say? Why yes! You can edit a file in GitLab, then commit the changes. Neat, huh?&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; title=&#34;return to article&#34;&gt; ↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A six-month update</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/a-six-month-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/a-six-month-update/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned &lt;a href=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/post/flux/&#34;&gt;last week&lt;/a&gt;, today is July 1&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt;, which marks a convenient half-way point for the year. On New Year&amp;rsquo;s Day, &lt;a href=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-fresh-starts/&#34;&gt;I posted a short list of goals&lt;/a&gt; that I was hoping to make progress towards. Here&amp;rsquo;s how it all breaks down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-post-something-here-every-friday&#34;&gt;1. Post something here every Friday.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, so good. I haven&amp;rsquo;t missed a single week, which I&amp;rsquo;m pretty pleased with. I&amp;rsquo;ll grant that it hasn&amp;rsquo;t always (ever?) been a particularly interesting read, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying hard to &lt;em&gt;keep showing up&lt;/em&gt;. Discipline isn&amp;rsquo;t easy, but it helps if you try to avoid &lt;a href=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-streaks/&#34;&gt;breaking the streak&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-post-to-a-journal-at-least-once-every-day&#34;&gt;2. Post to a journal at least once every day.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was doing pretty well with this through to the end of March, and gave up by April 22&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt;. It started well, but frankly, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t comfortable in writing my deepest thoughts into a service that can&amp;rsquo;t guarantee its privacy&amp;mdash;not that I think the fine folks at Bloom would &lt;em&gt;ever&lt;/em&gt; consider it, but if &lt;a href=&#34;http://dayoneapp.com/sync/&#34;&gt;key employees have access to the decrypted data&lt;/a&gt;, that means necessarily that there&amp;rsquo;s some risk of a data breach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I could feel it when I was writing, too&amp;mdash;I was self-censoring &lt;em&gt;just in case&lt;/em&gt;. And if you can&amp;rsquo;t just write whatever you want in your journal, of all places, then it&amp;rsquo;s not &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; a journal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I&amp;rsquo;ve deleted whatever I&amp;rsquo;d posted there, and I&amp;rsquo;m re-thinking this goal. There&amp;rsquo;s value to writing regularly, sure, and there&amp;rsquo;s value to getting your thoughts down, but between this blog, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://breakbeforemake.com/&#34;&gt;Break Before Make tumblr blog&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/angelostavrow&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, I think I&amp;rsquo;ve got more than enough opportunity to write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-make-real-progress-towards-my-mac-app&#34;&gt;3. Make real progress towards my Mac app.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Myeah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I settled on a name and registered a domain. I keep &lt;a href=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-moving-to-hugo-on-gitlab-pages/&#34;&gt;starting&lt;/a&gt; new &lt;a href=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/tags/tghr/&#34;&gt;projects&lt;/a&gt; and I&amp;rsquo;ve got even more in my Someday/Maybe list. I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; need to focus more on this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-contribute-to-open-source-projects&#34;&gt;4. Contribute to open-source projects.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like I haven&amp;rsquo;t done too much with this yet. I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;a href=&#34;https://about.gitlab.com/2016/03/10/setting-up-gitlab-ci-for-ios-projects/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;written&lt;/em&gt; for open-source projects&lt;/a&gt;, but beyond that, this also feels like something that&amp;rsquo;s maybe taking focus away from the Mac app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-get-in-better-shape&#34;&gt;5. Get in better shape.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After taking care of some knee issues with my physiotherapist, she gave me the green light to start getting active again. So, as of the end of March, I&amp;rsquo;ve started by jogging. My goal is to get in three 15-minute runs per week&amp;mdash;I&amp;rsquo;m not trying to run a marathon, just improve my cardiovascular health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been, well, shaky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve lapsed into no-run periods a few times, either because of an injury, or because I&amp;rsquo;ve been too lazy to get out and do it. But generally, there&amp;rsquo;s a very strong downward trend in my pace (from a 7:41 to a 6:17), so I&amp;rsquo;m happy. Moreover, it&amp;rsquo;s just been getting &lt;em&gt;easier&lt;/em&gt; to run for extended periods of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s high time I add some kind of strength training into the mix, though!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-salient-projects&#34;&gt;Other salient projects&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As linked above, other projects have come up that I started work on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For one, you may notice the new look of this site. As of today, it&amp;rsquo;s being built by &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; and is running on &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.gitlab.io/&#34;&gt;GitLab Pages&lt;/a&gt;. That&amp;rsquo;s been a fun little project, with the side benefit of saving me a few bucks a month, too. I&amp;rsquo;m considering cross-posting over to &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@angelostavrow&#34;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;, but we&amp;rsquo;ll see. There&amp;rsquo;s some theme work &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/AngeloStavrow/makebeforebreak.com/issues/12&#34;&gt;to be done&lt;/a&gt;, but otherwise, hello Hugo!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/AngeloStavrow/HoneyJar&#34;&gt;open-sourced my first iOS app&lt;/a&gt;, in the hopes that having it in public will embarrass me into updating it. But again, I really don&amp;rsquo;t want this to distract me from the Mac app I want to write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-s-next&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s next&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the intention is, for the next six months, to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;keep up with writing here, on (at least) a weekly basis;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;keep up with improving my general fitness and health; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;really get cracking on this Mac app I keep hinting at.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will I get sidetracked? Undoubtedly. Will I venture into new little projects that may or may not be abandoned? Yeah, it&amp;rsquo;s possible. We live &lt;a href=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/post/flux/&#34;&gt;in flux&lt;/a&gt;, after all, and it&amp;rsquo;s way more fun to explore the forest than it is to walk the path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Definitely more tk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flux</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/flux/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/flux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reminder: as of next week, the RSS feed for this site is moving! If you subscribe, please be sure to point your favourite reader to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://makebeforebreak.com/index.xml&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week is July the first. It&amp;rsquo;s Canada Day here, which means it&amp;rsquo;s a national holiday, but in Montreal, it&amp;rsquo;s also an unofficial moving day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;a propos&lt;/em&gt; that this site will be moving over to its new digs on that same day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But July first also marks the halfway point of the year, a year which I started &lt;a href=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/blog/2016/1/1/on-fresh-starts&#34;&gt;with some set of goals&lt;/a&gt;. So it&amp;rsquo;s also a good time to take stock of progress made against those goals, and make any necessary course-corrections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t intend on revisiting that here today, but I can tell you that I know that I haven&amp;rsquo;t made the kind of progress I was hoping for. In fact, the only thing I&amp;rsquo;ve &amp;ldquo;succeeded&amp;rdquo; at, strictly speaking, is posting something here every Friday. It hasn&amp;rsquo;t always been easy, but so far &lt;a href=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/blog/2016/4/22/on-streaks&#34;&gt;the streak has remained unbroken&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, technically, I&amp;rsquo;m looking at an 80% failure rate. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound encouraging at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could feel bad about this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I don&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ash Furrow gave &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.youtube.com/watch?v=hlLhtWLghGA&#34;&gt;a great talk called &lt;em&gt;Loosely Held Strong Convictions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; last year. It reminded me that, despite our belief to the contrary, we exist in a state of &lt;em&gt;flux&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s strange how we unconsciously fight this. I mean, we &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; that things&amp;mdash;including ourselves&amp;mdash;are constantly changing. And yet, we often try to plot rigid courses through life, despite the fact that today&amp;rsquo;s road may well be tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s fine to change your mind. In fact, it&amp;rsquo;s encouraged. It means you&amp;rsquo;re adaptable. You&amp;rsquo;re able to go beyond living your life as a to-do list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hard part in all of this, what I fight with the most, is whether or not I&amp;rsquo;m changing my mind because a path has become irrelevant, or just unpleasant. I may not be doing super well at getting to the gym (like, at all), but I &lt;em&gt;am&lt;/em&gt; trying to run for 15 minutes or so, three times a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except if it&amp;rsquo;s raining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or if I really need to get into the office soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or maybe if I woke up with a bit of a gurgle in my tummy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discipline is &lt;em&gt;hard&lt;/em&gt;. Which means it&amp;rsquo;s way more valuable than &lt;em&gt;motivation&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to do the pleasant thing when you&amp;rsquo;re motivated; it&amp;rsquo;s useful to do the unpleasant thing because you&amp;rsquo;re disciplined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, yeah. By all means, make changes to your opinions and your plans. But do it because it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea, not because it makes your life easier.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On moving to Hugo on GitLab Pages</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-moving-to-hugo-on-gitlab-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-moving-to-hugo-on-gitlab-pages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week, I took a hiatus from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/tags/tghr/&#34;&gt;refactoring fun&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve undertaken to (finally) move the blog over to a static site generator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/blog/2016/1/21/on-moving-preparations&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve written before&lt;/a&gt; about my plans to move to &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, and that&amp;rsquo;s now complete. Since the beginning of the year, all posts have been written as Markdown files that I can easily grab and format with the necessary front matter. Before then, I hadn&amp;rsquo;t written very much, and in fact I&amp;rsquo;ve dropped a couple of old posts that I felt didn&amp;rsquo;t add to the site in any way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site-generation files exist in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/AngeloStavrow/makebeforebreak.com&#34;&gt;GitLab repo&lt;/a&gt;. I treat this site as I would any other software project; &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/AngeloStavrow/makebeforebreak.com/issues&#34;&gt;issues&lt;/a&gt; are opened to add or modify things (including posts), a branch is created to address these issues, and when the work is done, the changes are merged into &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever something happens on &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt;, GitLab&amp;rsquo;s CI kicks in and a shared runner picks up the job, builds the site, and uploads the &lt;code&gt;public/&lt;/code&gt; folder to &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.gitlab.io&#34;&gt;GitLab Pages&lt;/a&gt;. This is one of the easiest ways to set up continuous deployment for the site, but when I started trying it out &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/gitlab-org/gitlab-ci-multi-runner/issues/1390&#34;&gt;there was an open issue&lt;/a&gt; to resolve for performance&amp;mdash;it could take hours before the changes went live. That&amp;rsquo;s gotten much better since GitLab 8.9RC3 was deployed, and I only make one post per week so it&amp;rsquo;s not that big a deal&amp;mdash;but if you need to keep things up-to-the-minute fresh it&amp;rsquo;s not a bad idea to set up a project-specific runner instead to build and deploy your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The official deploy date of the site is&amp;mdash;as you can see from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/AngeloStavrow/makebeforebreak.com/milestones/1&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;1.0&lt;/code&gt; milestone&lt;/a&gt;&amp;mdash;Friday, July 1&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One more thing: &lt;strong&gt;the RSS feed for this site will be changing.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;If&lt;/em&gt; you subscribe to the feed, &lt;strong&gt;please update your link&lt;/strong&gt; to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://makebeforebreak.com/index.xml
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More tk!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A moving update</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/a-moving-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/a-moving-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m in the process of (finally) finalizing the move of this site to &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, for real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most content is already in place. A few older posts need to be added, and some info pages are to be added. This is normal-priority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m using a slightly-modified built-in template to render the site. There a few more modifications to make, but this is low-priority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A commenting platform will be added. This is also normal-priority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to explore adding SSL to the site, but this is low-priority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, a deploy strategy is to be set up&amp;mdash;this is high-priority. The plan right now is to have the following workflow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Merge in some changes (i.e. New post, updating old content, &amp;amp;cet.);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Merge commit triggers CI to build the site;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When CI succeeds, deploy the built site to the web host.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will give me the opportunity to post from either my computer or my phone without issue. Then it&amp;rsquo;s just a question of reconfiguring DNS to serve up the new site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If all goes well, next week&amp;rsquo;s post should be on the new platform!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TGHR: Testing the units</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/tghr-testing-the-units/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/tghr-testing-the-units/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Great HoneyJar Refactoring&lt;/strong&gt; is a series of posts in which I take the first iOS app I ever wrote, &lt;a href=&#34;http://droppedbits.com/honeyjar/&#34;&gt;HoneyJar&lt;/a&gt;, and refactor it out of its original burning-dumpster-fire state and into a modern app. And I&#39;m doing it &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/AngeloStavrow/HoneyJar&#34;&gt;in public&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AngeloStavrow/status/738053482490527744&#34;&gt;I tweeted&lt;/a&gt; about my adventures in trying to add a test suite to HoneyJar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is this: I want to be sure that I&amp;rsquo;m not breaking anything in the app, as it exists right now, when I start refactoring. Without an existing test suite, I have no way of knowing if I&amp;rsquo;m creating any regressions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The TDD approach is to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write a test that checks a particular public method against a particular condition;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write the code that makes the test pass; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repeat steps 1 and 2 until you&amp;rsquo;re done writing the method / class / app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tests come first, and the code &amp;ldquo;fills in the blanks&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you&amp;rsquo;ve got a legacy codebase&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, however, does it still make sense to write failing tests first? Probably not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, what if it&amp;rsquo;s just not &lt;em&gt;possible&lt;/em&gt; to test certain methods or classes, because of the way the code is structured? If you haven&amp;rsquo;t written the code with testing in mind, then it might be too coupled or complex to test after the fact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stop writing legacy code. Do not write new features without unit testing. You are just making the code base worse and getting further away from introducing tests into your system. Get your testing infrastructure set up and a few tests running successfully and it will be much easier to think about introducing tests for the rest of the code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Dan Lee, &lt;a href=&#34;https://danlimerick.wordpress.com/2012/04/25/tdd-when-up-to-your-neck-in-legacy-code/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;TDD when up to your neck in legacy code&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, what&amp;rsquo;s making me a little bit crazy is that I&amp;rsquo;ll open a class to start adding some unit tests, see all kinds of ways to improve the code before adding the tests, and have to remind myself that I&amp;rsquo;ve made a promise not to touch the code until the test suite is in place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SO. FRUSTRATING.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;especially&lt;/em&gt; frustrating when you realize that you&amp;rsquo;d written something that you can&amp;rsquo;t really test, but you&amp;rsquo;re not allowing yourself to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we have a great way of getting around that. &lt;a href=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/blog/2016/5/13/on-comments&#34;&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m doing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the class to which I want to add tests;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a new test case class for said tests;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scan through the class under test and grind my teeth at obvious problems;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take three deep breaths;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start adding whatever tests that I can add without changing the code; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add thorough &lt;code&gt;//TODO&lt;/code&gt; comments on &amp;ldquo;next steps&amp;rdquo; for refactoring this class&amp;mdash;obvious problems, how to improve testability, &amp;amp;cet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to go through doing this for the entire codebase first. I &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; add some tests for a class, then refactor it, then move on to the next one, but then I have no way of knowing if I&amp;rsquo;m making a change that will somehow propagate through the app and trigger a failure elsewhere. So, while I&amp;rsquo;m not especially happy with the coverage I&amp;rsquo;m getting right now, it&amp;rsquo;s better this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/AngeloStavrow/HoneyJar/issues/2&#34;&gt;the issue is closed&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ll start tackling the actual refactoring&amp;mdash;and I&amp;rsquo;ll feel more like the project is ready for others to work on, too. For me, at least, I t&amp;rsquo;s really hard to make changes to a codebase I&amp;rsquo;m unfamiliar with if I don&amp;rsquo;t have the safety net of a test suite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, more tk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;footnote&#34; id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;By &#34;legacy codebase&#34;, here, we mean untested code, i.e., a codebase with no pre-existing test suite.&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; title=&#34;return to article&#34;&gt; ↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TGHR: Opening the source</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/tghr-opening-the-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/tghr-opening-the-source/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Great HoneyJar Refactoring&lt;/strong&gt; is a series of posts in which I take the first iOS app I ever wrote, &lt;a href=&#34;http://droppedbits.com/honeyjar/&#34;&gt;HoneyJar&lt;/a&gt;, and refactor it out of its original burning-dumpster-fire state and into a modern app. And I&#39;m doing it &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/AngeloStavrow/HoneyJar&#34;&gt;in public&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/blog/2016/5/20/the-great-honeyjar-refactoring&#34;&gt;Last week&lt;/a&gt; I introduced an idea I had: to open-source my first-ever iOS app, embarrassing as it might be, and refactor it out in the open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last week, I handled the open-sourcing of the app. This took a bit more time than I expected, and normally this should be done &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; releasing the project to the wild, but I figured it might be interesting to see just what the process was, what I learned, and some resources I found along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-starting-point&#34;&gt;The starting point&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HoneyJar, in its closed-source state, was very clearly an &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m learning as I go and am super excited to ship&amp;rdquo; kind of project. It had a &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/AngeloStavrow/HoneyJar/blob/4b5fa1653ac040ebe6f0896bd17b4ba463fc80aa/README.md&#34;&gt;README&lt;/a&gt;, kinda, which really just re-iterated some tagline-style description of the project, and that&amp;rsquo;s it. Unit tests were few and far between, comments were… &lt;a href=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/blog/2016/5/13/on-comments&#34;&gt;not awesome&lt;/a&gt;, and there was no real structure in place to make it useful for other contributors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the first step was to do exactly that. I opened the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/AngeloStavrow/HoneyJar/issues/1&#34;&gt;first issue&lt;/a&gt; and set up a task list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a CONTRIBUTING document&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a LICENSE document&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a CHANGELOG document&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update the README to provide more information on the project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up GitLab continuous integration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay. I know. That &lt;em&gt;sounds&lt;/em&gt; like a pretty straightforward list. Quick and easy to add. Turns out, you should put a little effort into these things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;readez-moi&#34;&gt;Readez-moi&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing most people will see in a project is the README file. This should provide some information on how to install/use the project, where to find further info on licensing and contributing, &amp;amp;cet. But how much info? What exactly do I need to add?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/PurpleBooth/109311bb0361f32d87a2&#34;&gt;an excellent template&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/PurpleBooth&#34;&gt;Billie Thompson&lt;/a&gt; that fits the bill nicely. While I&amp;rsquo;ve commented out a bunch of stuff that isn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily relevant (or maybe not relevant yet), I think it provides a pretty good overview of the what, who, why, and hows of the project. I&amp;rsquo;m relatively happy with the way the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/AngeloStavrow/HoneyJar/blob/master/README.md&#34;&gt;README&lt;/a&gt; turned out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;with-every-change-log-log-log&#34;&gt;With every change, log, log, log&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up: everyone&amp;rsquo;s favourite, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/AngeloStavrow/HoneyJar/blob/master/CHANGELOG.md&#34;&gt;CHANGELOG&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, seriously. This either gets totally overlooked, or totally becomes a series of punchlines about episodes of Friends or whatever. In trying to figure out what needs to go into a change log, I discovered &lt;a href=&#34;http://keepachangelog.com/&#34;&gt;Keep A CHANGLELOG&lt;/a&gt;. Great resource.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you go through merging in changes, part of the merge should including updating the change log with whatever you&amp;rsquo;ve, well, changed. As the project maintainers indicate, typical sections are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Added&lt;/code&gt; for new features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Changed&lt;/code&gt; for changes in existing functionality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Deprecated&lt;/code&gt; for once-stable features removed in upcoming releases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Removed&lt;/code&gt; for deprecated features removed in this release.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Fixed&lt;/code&gt; for any bug fixes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Security&lt;/code&gt; to invite users to upgrade in case of vulnerabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally&amp;mdash;I love this&amp;mdash; every subtitle of the document should be a link to a &lt;code&gt;git compare&lt;/code&gt; of the previous and current tags (or &lt;code&gt;HEAD&lt;/code&gt;, if you&amp;rsquo;re working on an unreleased version).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excellent idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;license-to-thrive&#34;&gt;License to thrive&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.codinghorror.com/pick-a-license-any-license/&#34;&gt;Jeff Atwood said it in 5 words&lt;/a&gt;. Pick a license. This is important, or you&amp;rsquo;re pretty much putting your work out there without letting anyone know if they can use it. Picking a license helps you both cut the overhead of having to reply to emails (&amp;ldquo;can I use this code?&amp;rdquo;) while putting down some ground rules on how your work can be used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went with a simple &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/AngeloStavrow/HoneyJar/blob/master/LICENSE&#34;&gt;3-clause BSD license&lt;/a&gt;. Essentially, this is a use-as-is-without-warranty license, requiring attribution by others who redistribute your work, and written permission if they want to use my name (or my organization&amp;rsquo;s name) in any endorsement or promotion of their derived products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;just-add-contributors&#34;&gt;Just add contributors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hardest to set up was the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/AngeloStavrow/HoneyJar/blob/master/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;CONTRIBUTING&lt;/a&gt; document. Here, there are two main things I wanted to address:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expectations of all involved (i.e., a code of conduct), and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; to contribute.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The how-to-contribute part is pretty straightforward. Everything should start with an issue, and once labels and owners are assigned, work can begin. There&amp;rsquo;s some basic info on how to report a bug vs. how to add a feature request, and I added some requirements for merge requests too. Such requirements can get pretty complex and involved, but it&amp;rsquo;s important to step back and examine the scope of the project too. We&amp;rsquo;re not building CocoaPods here; a tiny not-super-important project like HoneyJar probably won&amp;rsquo;t attract much in the way of contributions, so there&amp;rsquo;s no need for overly complex requirements for making changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I believe that &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; project, regardless of size, has the potential for community. And a community is only as good as the expectations for interaction. In my work, as in my life, I really try to come from a position of trust, mindfulness, and open-ness, so putting together a code of conduct that embraces these values is important to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, I&amp;rsquo;m not the only one that feels this way. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://contributor-covenant.org/version/1/4/code_of_conduct.md&#34;&gt;Contributor Covenant&lt;/a&gt; is a good place to start, and other open-source communities (&lt;a href=&#34;https://thoughtbot.com/open-source-code-of-conduct&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/CocoaPods/CocoaPods/blob/master/CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://swift.org/community/&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;, as examples) have done a great job of adapting it. I&amp;rsquo;ve followed in their footsteps, and I think the code of conduct section nicely explains the let&amp;rsquo;s-be-wonderful-to-each-other feels that I want in my community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;all-the-great-fails&#34;&gt;All the great fails&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last thing I absolutely wanted up and running for this first issue was to get continuous integration up and running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But Angelo, you don&amp;rsquo;t have a test suite set up for your project.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I know. But the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/AngeloStavrow/HoneyJar/issues/2&#34;&gt;next big step&lt;/a&gt; before I start working on the actual refactoring is &lt;em&gt;exactly that&lt;/em&gt;: add a test suite for existing code. It would be downright silly to try refactoring something without making sure that you&amp;rsquo;re not breaking anything as you go through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I followed &lt;a href=&#34;https://about.gitlab.com/2016/03/10/setting-up-gitlab-ci-for-ios-projects/&#34;&gt;the steps in the article I wrote&lt;/a&gt; and created a new runner and a &lt;code&gt;.gitlab-ci.yml&lt;/code&gt; file, along with some sample test, to make sure everything&amp;rsquo;s working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And builds kept getting stuck with the error:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Failed to authorize rights (0x1) with status: -60007.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out, &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/gitlab-org/gitlab-ci-multi-runner/issues/1143&#34;&gt;I needed to update the runner on my build machine&lt;/a&gt; to address some changes in Xcode 7.3&amp;mdash;once that was done, things started building as expected. One of the great things about GitLab being an open-source project is that if you&amp;rsquo;re running into trouble, there&amp;rsquo;s likely an issue available to help you figure out what&amp;rsquo;s happening and how to fix it (and if there isn&amp;rsquo;t, open one!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve left the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/AngeloStavrow/HoneyJar/builds&#34;&gt;build history&lt;/a&gt; as-is, along with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/AngeloStavrow/HoneyJar/commits/9a3e8202b2dab26bf2ed45251918cfa5c844b0fc&#34;&gt;commit history&lt;/a&gt;, as breadcrumbs to how I managed to get things working, along with the stupid mistakes like overlooked typos in your runner tags. I don&amp;rsquo;t think there&amp;rsquo;s any value in trying to hide these goofs, because they could be invaluable the next time you&amp;rsquo;re yelling at your system for not &lt;em&gt;just working come on you stupid thing everything was fine a minute ago what do you mean this tag doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;onwards-and-upwards&#34;&gt;Onwards and upwards&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the project is now, IMO, officially open-sourced. The next big step is to add the test suite, and &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; I can move on to the fun stuff: refactoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More tk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Great HoneyJar Refactoring</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/the-great-honeyjar-refactoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/the-great-honeyjar-refactoring/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Thinking about a series of posts where I take HoneyJar, the first iOS app I wrote, and refactor it out of its burning-dumpster-fire state.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Angelo Stavrow (@AngeloStavrow) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AngeloStavrow/status/732279293464678400&#34;&gt;May 16, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next few weeks, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to write a series of posts about taking my first iOS app, &lt;a href=&#34;https://droppedbits.com/honeyjar&#34;&gt;HoneyJar&lt;/a&gt;, and refactoring it from its current (terrible) state into something, well, less-terrible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I plan on doing it &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/AngeloStavrow/HoneyJar&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;in public&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m calling this project &lt;strong&gt;The Great HoneyJar Refactoring&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HoneyJar is a future-value calculator. As explained on the product page, you set a payment amount, a rate of return, and a period of time, and HoneyJar will give you a scenario showing how your money will grow if the amount entered amount was&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a one-time lump-sum payment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a series of equal weekly payments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a series of equal monthly payments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t really touched it after I released 1.0 save for a few minor updates. It could certainly use some love, as there&amp;rsquo;s a whole lot of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Technical_debt&#34;&gt;technical debt&lt;/a&gt; going on in that codebase. Just off the top of my head, without having poked around the repository for months, I can list the following required fixes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refactor the main UIViewController into several lighter classes. The thing is a mess.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Along a similar line, convert the project to use Storyboards and Autolayout.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a test suite.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add localization (I&amp;rsquo;ll start with English and French, since I speak those languages pretty fluently).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure accessibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Port the thing to Swift, or at least write new code in Swift.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General UI/UX improvements (e.g., make the result presentation clearer).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drop support for devices running iOS 8 and before.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to call this version 2.0 and I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/AngeloStavrow/HoneyJar/milestones/1&#34;&gt;opened a milestone in GitLab&lt;/a&gt; to track my progress. The associated issues will be added over the next day or two, so you can see how what I&amp;rsquo;m working on at any given time. I&amp;rsquo;ll also be setting up CI and other (non-code) project settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I&amp;rsquo;m open-sourcing the (embarrassing) version as it exists right now&amp;mdash;&lt;em&gt;please be nice&lt;/em&gt;&amp;mdash;and I plan on tackling one issue every couple of weeks or so, until the milestone is closed and 2.0 is released. Each time I close an issue, I&amp;rsquo;ll write up a post on the whys and wherefores of the changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet decided if I&amp;rsquo;ll accept any merge requests during this project, but I certainly look forward to feedback on my work. To make it easier for people, to follow along, I will be mirroring the repository &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/DroppedBits/HoneyJar&#34;&gt;on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, too&amp;mdash;GitLab makes it easy to push changes to a remote repo. GitLab is my &lt;code&gt;origin&lt;/code&gt; of choice, though, thanks to the built-in continuous integration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update (2016-05-25):&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve moved the GitHub mirror from my personal account to the organization account, since it&amp;rsquo;s Dropped Bits that&amp;rsquo;s handling the App Store stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More tk!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On comments</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-comments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&#34;(http://www.makebeforebreak.com/blog/2016/4/29/on-interruption-driven-development)&#34;&gt;mentioned&lt;/a&gt; that keeping comments up-to-date with modifications in source code helps me with task-switching in a busy workplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make a difference if you&amp;rsquo;re not commenting your code &lt;em&gt;well&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therein lies the rub. I spent weeks on learning various sorting algorithms in my data structures and algorithms class, but I never really learned anything on the whys and wherefores of commenting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been taught that&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;// This is an inline comment.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and that&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;/* This is a block comment, which makes
 * longer comments a little bit more
 * readable.
 */
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and also how to use comments to temporarily disable portions of your source code to try something out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what should you put &lt;em&gt;in&lt;/em&gt; your comments?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visual Studio has a neat feature where if you type three slashes in a row (&lt;code&gt;///&lt;/code&gt;) before a method definition, it&amp;rsquo;ll expand a comment snippet that includes, as appropriate, sections for a &lt;em&gt;summary&lt;/em&gt;, what method argument &lt;em&gt;parameters&lt;/em&gt; are, and what the method &lt;em&gt;returns&lt;/em&gt;. Whatever you enter there shows up in a tool tip when you hover over the method call later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, three slashes (&lt;code&gt;///&lt;/code&gt;) in Xcode will allow you to enter comments that show up when you hover over method calls.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Handy, for sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, really, when I&amp;rsquo;m heads down and trying to push code out before, say, I leave for the day, I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that all I write in these comments is a re-iteration of the method signature&amp;mdash;and given that I try to use very descriptive method and variable names in the first place, these extra lines of typing are pretty redundant. I&amp;rsquo;m just giving myself work for zero added benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;My point here is that if you have trouble expressing basic intent of code then there are bigger issues with it &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/YcyuvQQxSH&#34;&gt;https://t.co/YcyuvQQxSH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Mx.Samantha (@queersorceress) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/queersorceress/status/730484670027186176&#34;&gt;May 11, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Samantha&amp;rsquo;s tweet inspired me to think a bit more about how I comment my code. Intent is key, I agree. If the source code is the documentation&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, then the comments should probably play the role of both the chapter summaries, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; the sidebars that warn of the gotchas, the perils, and the pitfalls. The bigger-picture stuff. &lt;em&gt;Why&lt;/em&gt; is this structured this way? &lt;em&gt;What&lt;/em&gt; might I have to look out for when testing this particular method?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the best practices we learn&amp;mdash;design patterns, unit testing, &amp;amp;cet.&amp;mdash;are meant to make our code more maintainable. Comments should be an integral part of that, not just as a repetition of what&amp;rsquo;s obvious from the source, but as a reflection of the intent of the thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li class=&#34;footnote&#34; id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You definitely should pick up Erica Sadun&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://leanpub.com/swiftdocumentationmarkup&#34;&gt;Swift Documentation Markup&lt;/a&gt; to really make the most of this feature, by the way.&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; title=&#34;return to article&#34;&gt; ↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;footnote&#34; id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I&#39;m not 100% convinced of this particular mantra. Of course, code is the canonical source of ground truth, and that&#39;s the intent, but as far as it being documentation&amp;mdash;well, that&#39;s a post for another day.&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; title=&#34;return to article&#34;&gt; ↩&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On delays</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-delays/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-delays/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/blog/2016/1/21/on-moving-preparations&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve discussed the transition over to a static-site generator before&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I&amp;rsquo;m still planning on doing this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s been a long time coming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m setting a deadline for myself: the next post on this blog will be with the new setup. It probably won&amp;rsquo;t have all the pieces in place re: design and other &lt;a href=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/blog/2016/3/18/on-sitemaps-for-roadp&#34;&gt;related-site plans&lt;/a&gt;, but I&amp;rsquo;ve got to start somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More tk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On interruption-driven development</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-interruption-driven-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-interruption-driven-development/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the sole developer at work, I have to balance our “ask me anything, anytime” culture with a need for unbroken concentration on whatever code I&amp;rsquo;m writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m generally fine with a door-always-open policy like this, because it makes communication fast and easy&amp;mdash;especially in a small team, where everyone wears several hats&amp;mdash;but as projects get closer to a deadline, it does tend to put a bit of strain on my ability to get things done. When that project involves a relatively complex application, however, it can be very hard to keep things on schedule, because &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.joelonsoftware.com/articles/fog0000000022.html&#34;&gt;task switching has such a high cost&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s because programming is the kind of task where you have to keep a lot of things in your head at once. The more things you remember at once, the more productive you are at programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been struggling with this a little bit lately. It&amp;rsquo;s no one&amp;rsquo;s fault, of course&amp;mdash;colleagues are just interacting with each other the way they always have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying some of the more common workarounds to this kind of workflow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;coming in to work two hours earlier than anyone else to focus on trickier problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;working from home&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;declining meeting requests that I don&amp;rsquo;t absolutely need to join&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;delegating other tasks to other colleagues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;using noise-attenuating headphones when I need peak focus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s helping somewhat, but what I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed as the project approaches release-candidate is a little more interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The more loosely-coupled the code is, the easier it is to come back to it after an interruption.&lt;/strong&gt; Instead of having to keep all kinds of interaction in my head, I love small, simple classes that have no knowledge of their context. They do one or two related things, and that&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;it&lt;/em&gt;. Jumping in and out of these is relatively easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A good debugger and a test suite are indispensible.&lt;/strong&gt; Interrupted tasks are &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ninlabs.com/2013/01/programmer-interrupted/&#34;&gt;twice as likely to contain errors&lt;/a&gt;, so a thorough test suite&amp;mdash;and really writing tests before code, as TDD requires&amp;mdash;helps catch these. Some parts of my project include firmware that&amp;rsquo;s written without the benefits of test frameworks or breakpoints, so I have to resort to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ecnmag.com/blog/2015/06/debugging-caveman&#34;&gt;caveman debugging&lt;/a&gt;. This is something I&amp;rsquo;m going to avoid in future projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Refactor your comments with your code.&lt;/strong&gt; You should never trust your comments to accurately reflect what your code does unless you consider them to be inseparable from the code, and change them while you make changes to your code. When you&amp;rsquo;re interrupted, ask for a minute to take a note on what you&amp;rsquo;re doing and add &lt;code&gt;TODO:&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;FIXME:&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;HAX:&lt;/code&gt; comments that you can come back to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These things do way more for my ability to mitigate how badly an interruption affects my productivity than headphones, working from home, or refusing meetings, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; they make my code better to boot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What works best for you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;footnote&#34; id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;This is difficult, because the software I’m working on has to control some permanently-installed hardware in our lab.&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; title=&#34;return to article&#34;&gt; ↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On streaks</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-streaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-streaks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the 17&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; post made to this blog since the beginning of 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That means that I&amp;rsquo;ve posted something every Friday since the start of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AngeloStavrow/status/723268757825720322&#34;&gt;I suggested that I might not be posting anything today&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve been feeling a bit tired lately as deadlines loom for work projects, so personal side-projects tend to slip a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, dammit, the idea of not breaking a streak—especially four months in—really does work as a motivator to keep things going. This may be far from a daily habit, and I imagine most people wouldn&amp;rsquo;t notice if I missed a week, but I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t bring myself to leave a gap in my posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because that&amp;rsquo;s how it starts for me—skip one entry, and then I&amp;rsquo;ve subconsciously given myself permission to drop the project entirely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s okay to drop projects, but I feel that should be a conscious decision made when you&amp;rsquo;re taking stock of what&amp;rsquo;s going on in the entirety of your life, not some subconscious decision from a contextless state of mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, yeah. Post number seventeen. Streaks work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On getting there</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-getting-there/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-getting-there/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A short post today, based on a realization I had earlier this week at &lt;a href=&#34;http://cocoaheadsmtl.com/&#34;&gt;CocoaHeads&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like many, I often suffer from &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Impostor_syndrome&#34;&gt;impostor syndrome&lt;/a&gt;. It hits when I&amp;rsquo;m tackling something new that I &lt;em&gt;thought&lt;/em&gt; built on previous knowledge, leaving me feeling a bit bewildered, and undermining my confidence in having mastered lesser matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually, I take a walk and come back to the problem with a clearer head, and will work my way through it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that I&amp;rsquo;ve always worked as a solo developer, with no formal computer science or software engineering background, I&amp;rsquo;ve always felt a bit iffy about my programming chops. I do my best to emulate what I see, but sometimes can&amp;rsquo;t shake the feeling that the code I write is amateur and inelegant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I look back at old code and think it&amp;rsquo;s garbage. This should probably be seen as an indicator that I&amp;rsquo;m progressing, but it sometimes just reinforces the &amp;ldquo;you&amp;rsquo;re a hack&amp;rdquo; feelings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Tuesday, looking at some of the code presented in the demos, I realized that people were writing code &lt;em&gt;the same way I would have written it&lt;/em&gt;. Maybe some stylistic differences, sure, but generally, it turns out that I&amp;rsquo;m at a point where my approach to writing code is getting there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess the point is that, eventually, you get there. A year ago, if I had to show code to someone, I would have been making all manner of apologies for it. While I&amp;rsquo;m still pretty far from mastery, it&amp;rsquo;s reassuring to see the improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, you know. Just keep swimming.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On subscription software</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-subscription-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-subscription-software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday of this week, Smile Software announced that their &lt;a href=&#34;https://smilesoftware.com/software-releases/entry/the-new-textexpander&#34;&gt;TextExpander software would be switching to a subscription model&lt;/a&gt;. As a longtime user and big fan of TextExpander, I have some thoughts on this change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another bit of software that I&amp;rsquo;m a huge fan of, YNAB, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youneedabudget.com/blog/post/the-new-ynab-is-here&#34;&gt;made a similar switch&lt;/a&gt; at the end of 2015&amp;mdash;no more desktop apps sold with traditional licenses, but rather a new web app with a yearly subscription.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They&amp;rsquo;re hardly the first to abandon the paid-up-front/paid-upgrade business model. And it&amp;rsquo;s not just a question of small software publishers that trying on a new pricing option to improve cash flow. Most famously, Microsoft and Adobe moved to subscription models for Office and CC, respectively. While Microsoft still sells traditional one-time-purchase licenses for Office, that may not be an option forever&amp;mdash;it&amp;rsquo;s clear that they want you to move to their subscription model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some believe that subscription models are the most logical conclusion for sustainable revenue. Certainly, it &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; make income more predictable: it more-or-less normalizes revenue across the fiscal year, moving away from the typical huge-spike-at-launch (followed by smaller spikes on paid upgrades) sales patterns. When a business can better predict income, it can better plan resource allocation and feature releases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is something that web-service businesses have been doing from the outset&amp;mdash;monthly fees (with, perhaps, a discounted yearly fee) are the norm. I can only think of &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; service (&lt;a href=&#34;https://pinboard.in&#34;&gt;Pinboard&lt;/a&gt;) that &lt;em&gt;used&lt;/em&gt; to charge a one-time, paid-up-front fee (although even that &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.pinboard.in/2014/11/new_pricing_policy/&#34;&gt;has changed&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But charging a monthly fee does not sustainable revenue make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least, I don&amp;rsquo;t think it does for a large segment of the market. Monthly fees are something that are far easier to justify when they&amp;rsquo;re mission critical&amp;mdash;which typically means software that helps a business improve cash flow. They can look at a cost/benefit ratio and determine that the net result is positive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vast majority of software does not fall in this category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I don&amp;rsquo;t think this is the largest impediment for software publishers going to a monthly fee. An even more interesting problem that comes with transitioning to a subscription model is that it takes the renewal-timing decision out of users&amp;rsquo; control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nerds like myself will &lt;em&gt;probably&lt;/em&gt; upgrade to the latest version of software the day it&amp;rsquo;s released, but smart people will weigh the pros and cons and see if it&amp;rsquo;s a worthwhile upgrade. Even if it is, a user can decide that they&amp;rsquo;ll keep using the current version awhile longer, if only because it improves their total cost of ownership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sven Fechner illustrates this nicely &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/simplicitybliss/status/717746576718999557&#34;&gt;in his tweet on the TCO of TextExpander Classic vs. TextExpander 6&lt;/a&gt;. Taken over a longer period of time, with the traditional pricing model, users could opt to upgrade every eighteen months or even two years (assuming yearly upgrades) and save even more money. Or, at least, improve cash flow a bit by delaying some upgrades so that they don&amp;rsquo;t all fall around the same time of year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, with a subscription, what happens now is that I have no influence on when the lump-sum yearly payments will become due (unless there&amp;rsquo;s an option for a monthly fee, I guess, but that&amp;rsquo;s usually the more expensive option).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, instead, I&amp;rsquo;m forced to create a &amp;ldquo;subscription software&amp;rdquo; budget category and start putting aside some amount to cover next year&amp;rsquo;s fee&amp;mdash;or worse, come renewal time, I&amp;rsquo;m taken by surprise when I see a the fee I forgot about charged to my credit card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can tell you this: as that subscription software category starts to grow, some hard choices will be made. YNAB will stay because the money it saves me is at least an order of magnitude over what it costs me. TextExpander? Well, it&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;em&gt;great&lt;/em&gt; utility, but I don&amp;rsquo;t know that I can justify a yearly fee for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get that it&amp;rsquo;s tough for smaller/indie developers to make a sustainable income from their apps, but the reality of the market is borne out by the App Store: cheap/free apps are what get the downloads. So, businesses are forced to try new things, so that they can afford to keep making the software that we use and love. At the end of the day, the only people who are &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; willing to pay sustainable prices for software are software developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paul Haddad &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/tapbot_paul/status/717341611932266496&#34;&gt;tweeted some possible outcomes&lt;/a&gt; of TextExpander&amp;rsquo;s pricing experiment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I think that subscription software is a phase that some parts of the industry are trying on for size, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any staying power &lt;em&gt;unless&lt;/em&gt; there&amp;rsquo;s a radical shift in the way we consume software. Something like, for example, an &lt;em&gt;App Store subscription&lt;/em&gt;. We&amp;rsquo;re moving to music and TV/movie subscriptions anyhow; maybe&amp;mdash;just maybe&amp;mdash;one way to make this work would be to pay Apple a monthly fee for access to any app on the App Stores?&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An interesting note: Smile have &lt;a href=&#34;https://smilesoftware.com/blog/entry/textexpander-release-follow-up&#34;&gt;made sure to clarify&lt;/a&gt; that TextExpander 5 will continue to be supported for at least one more OS X version. It&amp;rsquo;s clear that they&amp;rsquo;re listening to the feedback they&amp;rsquo;re getting from their users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;footnote&#34; id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I realize that on the Mac, this wouldn’t work for apps like TextExpander, as they cannot break out of the sandbox restrictions required by the Mac App Store to do what they do.&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; title=&#34;return to article&#34;&gt; ↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On sweating the small stuff</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-sweating-the-small-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-sweating-the-small-stuff/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I hear &lt;em&gt;ship it&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;we&amp;rsquo;ll fix it in post&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;, I get that the intended sentiment is  that &lt;em&gt;perfect is the enemy of done&lt;/em&gt;. But too often, this translates to &lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m okay with shipping garbage&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a delicate balance to be struck between &lt;a href=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/blog/2014/6/19/festina-lente&#34;&gt;doing it quickly vs. doing it well&lt;/a&gt;, sure, but if you&amp;rsquo;re having a hard time getting there, then maybe you&amp;rsquo;ve bitten off more than you can chew. And that&amp;rsquo;s a whole other kettle of fish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it doesn&amp;rsquo;t just come down to outwardly sloppiness, either. When it comes down to your shipped product, people won&amp;rsquo;t necessarily notice features that didn&amp;rsquo;t ship&amp;mdash;but every lapse from perfection &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; be noticed, and will go against your credibility as a Maker Of Great Things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://about.gitlab.com/2015/12/07/why-we-shift-objectives-and-not-release-dates-at-gitlab/&#34;&gt;GitLab has an interesting take on shipping&lt;/a&gt;. They have time-based releases (the 22nd of every month), rather than feature-based releases. If a feature isn&amp;rsquo;t ready for the next point-upgrade, it gets pushed to the one after. No big deal. This way, the only thing that ships is what&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;truly&lt;/em&gt; ready from prime time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like this approach, and it works well in the continuous-delivery context of a web app, but I think the lesson applies more broadly, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t ship for the sake of shipping. It becomes pretty clear pretty quickly that the product is taking a backseat to the profits when you do so. And the product always has to come first.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On iterative learning</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-iterative-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-iterative-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week, I had a chance to talk out my approach to learning new things in the context of Cocoa development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always found that I learn best when I get to &lt;a href=&#34;http://english.stackexchange.com/questions/30939/is-used-in-anger-a-britishism-for-something&#34;&gt;use it in anger&lt;/a&gt;, but when it comes to something as big and sprawling as the Cocoa framework, there&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of stuff to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that I do the vast majority of my development solo, I&amp;rsquo;ve found that the best way to approach this is to break the framework down into manageable chunks, write a little project based around that chunk, and then ship it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote my first app, &lt;a href=&#34;http://droppedbits.com/honeyjar&#34;&gt;HoneyJar&lt;/a&gt;, as a first introduction to &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/library/mac/documentation/Cocoa/Conceptual/ProgrammingWithObjectiveC/Introduction/Introduction.html#//apple_ref/doc/uid/TP40011210-CH1-SW1&#34;&gt;Objective-C&lt;/a&gt; and Xcode. IDEs like Xcode are generally pretty similar&amp;mdash;at their core, they&amp;rsquo;re text editors with some special features&amp;mdash;but Objective-C looked like no other programming language I&amp;rsquo;d ever seen before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;- (void)doYouKnowTheMuffinMan:(TheMuffinMan)theMuffinMan;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(I saw this somewhere on Twitter and I wish I could remember who to credit for it!)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also made the app iPhone-only, as this made for a much less complex platform as far as things like filesystems, window sizes, and interaction go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also took the opportunity to explore &lt;a href=&#34;https://cocoapods.org&#34;&gt;CocoaPods&lt;/a&gt;, adding some libraries to handle some view and viewcontroller tasks&amp;mdash;I had my hands full trying to figure out the language and the platform. I also integrated &lt;a href=&#34;http://hockeyapp.net/features/&#34;&gt;HockeyApp&lt;/a&gt; into the beta version I was working on, to get feedback from friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I was relatively happy with the app, I revved it to 1.0 and submitted it to the App Store&amp;mdash;again, something I&amp;rsquo;d never done before. HoneyJar was never expected to be some kind of successful product, but a few people have downloaded it, and I know it&amp;rsquo;s been useful to me on occasion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Apple &lt;a href=&#34;https://swift.org/&#34;&gt;announced Swift&lt;/a&gt;, its new programming language, I got pretty excited. Swift certainly &lt;em&gt;looked&lt;/em&gt; a lot more like the programming languages I was familiar with, and there was something really neat about &amp;ldquo;growing up&amp;rdquo; with a new language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I started work on my next app, &lt;a href=&#34;http://droppedbits.com/per&#34;&gt;Per&lt;/a&gt;. Per was all about digging into Swift (which has changed dramatically since the app was written)&amp;mdash;there are no external libraries used anywhere in the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also used it as an opportunity to play with some animations when presenting and dismissing view controllers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://static1.squarespace.com/static/53ebc004e4b0aa86f612f6fd/t/54ea85a1e4b08f2aaf399192/1424655859170/unit-conversion.gif?format=500w&#34; alt=&#34;Per&#39;s unit-converter feature&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This meant that I got to look into &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/library/ios/documentation/Swift/Conceptual/Swift_Programming_Language/Closures.html&#34;&gt;closures&lt;/a&gt; as well, again as a small chunk of their applicability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week I wrote about &lt;a href=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/blog/2016/3/11/on-writing-for-gitlab&#34;&gt;writing for GitLab&lt;/a&gt; as a means of teaching myself more about their continuous integration features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m now interested in working with &lt;a href=&#34;https://fastlane.tools/&#34;&gt;fastlane tools&lt;/a&gt;, so I&amp;rsquo;m working on an app as a counterpart to &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/gitlab-com/blog-posts/issues/169&#34;&gt;a new article I&amp;rsquo;ll be writing for GitLab&lt;/a&gt;. The app is relatively simple: it consumes GitLab&amp;rsquo;s  API to present some kind of a dashboard for project milestones that the user is involved in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I want to focus on learning fastlane, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to worry &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; much about handling API requests and responses, so I&amp;rsquo;m using a great library called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Alamofire/Alamofire&#34;&gt;Alamofire&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m making this a &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/tvos/&#34;&gt;tvOS app&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why tvOS?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, firstly, it&amp;rsquo;s a new platform that I get to play with. That&amp;rsquo;s pretty interesting in and of itself, because while it brings a standardized screen size, it also includes the Siri remote as the sole means of interaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, additionally, an Apple TV assumes a persistent connection to the internet, which means one less thing to worry about: testing for a lack of connectivity (or worse, &lt;em&gt;spotty&lt;/em&gt; connectivity).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This way, I can learn about a new platform and a new toolchain without worrying about other pitfalls and perils.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;rsquo;s how I like to learn: small, neatly defined chunks, where I can focus on the thing I want to find out about, and ship something that showcases what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned. I&amp;rsquo;d love to know what works best for you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On roadmaps for sitemaps</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-roadmaps-for-sitemaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-roadmaps-for-sitemaps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;a href=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/blog/2016/1/21/on-moving-preparations&#34;&gt;mentioned before&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;m looking into re-working things a little bit for some of my &amp;ldquo;online presence&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now my personal site is just a static landing page. It&amp;rsquo;s generated by &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; and links to other things (this blog, my Tumblr, GitLab/GitHub, Twitter, &amp;amp;cet.)—and I think it&amp;rsquo;s time to start consolidating some of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog will be moving to a static-site generator soon, too (again, Hugo). The domain and all links will remain active, but I&amp;rsquo;d like it to also live under a &lt;code&gt;/blog&lt;/code&gt; directory on my personal site. I&amp;rsquo;ll continue to write longer-form posts here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Tumblr, &lt;a href=&#34;http://breakbeforemake&#34;&gt;Break Before Make&lt;/a&gt;, will shift roles to becoming more of a linkblog—I have a huge backlog of stuff in Instapaper that I want to start sharing, and I think this is probably a better option than &lt;a href=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/blog/2016/2/5/on-reading-lists&#34;&gt;starting a newsletter&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;d also like to pull those posts into the &lt;code&gt;/blog&lt;/code&gt; directory, between the MBB posts. It&amp;rsquo;ll stay on Tumblr because I like its sharing capabilities via its iOS app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also think of adding &lt;a href=&#34;http://nownownow.com/about&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;/now&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;code&gt;/using&lt;/code&gt; pages to my personal site, to discuss my projects and my tools, respectively. The former is &lt;em&gt;supposed&lt;/em&gt; to keep you focussed on &lt;em&gt;what you&amp;rsquo;re doing&lt;/em&gt;, which &lt;a href=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/blog/2016/1/24/on-focus&#34;&gt;I often need help with&lt;/a&gt;; the latter I&amp;rsquo;m not sure about, because really, I&amp;rsquo;m more interested in results than I am in tools—but maybe workflows will be of interest to some.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;rsquo;s the plan. Initially I&amp;rsquo;d hoped to have completed at least moving this site to a static generator by the end of February, but, well… time makes fools of us all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More tk…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On writing for GitLab</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-writing-for-gitlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-writing-for-gitlab/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, an article I wrote on setting up &lt;a href=&#34;https://about.gitlab.com/2016/03/10/setting-up-gitlab-ci-for-ios-projects/&#34;&gt;GitLab CI for your iOS projects&lt;/a&gt; was posted on the GitLab blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I&amp;rsquo;m a relative newcomer to continuous integration, but I know that it&amp;rsquo;s valuable. And I also know that GitLab&amp;rsquo;s feature is free, regardless of whether your project is public or private.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also know that the best way to learn something is to show someone else how to do it—so I launched BBEdit and took notes as I worked my way through the setup, with the intention of posting something here about my experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I discovered GitLab&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://about.gitlab.com/2016/01/26/call-for-writers/&#34;&gt;call for writers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;gitlab-runs-gitlab-on-gitlab-to-continuously-improve-gitlab&#34;&gt;GitLab runs GitLab on GitLab to continuously improve GitLab&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GitLab is more than just a version-control system. It&amp;rsquo;s a community. I deployed their Community Edition on a work server back around v3 and it&amp;rsquo;s been in use ever since, partly because it&amp;rsquo;s nice to have your own internal DVCS, and partly because of the predictable roll-outs of new versions (every month, on the 22nd), which makes scheduled maintenance easy to plan for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the key reason is that it&amp;rsquo;s always been more than just a DVCS. I&amp;rsquo;ve watched GitLab grow from its humble beginnings to, in my mind, one of the most interesting open-source projects out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you can see the value of this kind of Extreme Dogfooding in the bug report response time and the cool new features that come around with every point release. But you also see it in their &lt;a href=&#34;https://about.gitlab.com/strategy/&#34;&gt;strategy document&lt;/a&gt;. And their &lt;a href=&#34;https://about.gitlab.com/handbook/&#34;&gt;team handbook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-all-starts-with-an-issue&#34;&gt;It all starts with an issue&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether talking about &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/gitlab-org/gitlab-ce/issues/12712&#34;&gt;a bug report&lt;/a&gt; or a blog post, &lt;a href=&#34;https://about.gitlab.com/2016/03/03/start-with-an-issue/&#34;&gt;everything starts with the opening an issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After applying to their call for writers, I heard back from Heather, GitLab&amp;rsquo;s Developer Marketing Manager, who assigned me to &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/gitlab-com/blog-posts/issues/29&#34;&gt;an issue on the topic&lt;/a&gt;. I proposed an outline of the post, and after some discussion and clarification on the topic, I forked the GitLab-website repo and began work on my draft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything is done publicly, in the open. This means that everyone can contribute, and you can easily send links to conversations and drafts to peers for comment and review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;wip-it-good&#34;&gt;WIP it good&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so the writing commenced. A few days later, I &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/gitlab-com/www-gitlab-com/merge_requests/1567&#34;&gt;opened a Merge Request&lt;/a&gt; with a commit of my first draft. By adding &lt;code&gt;[WIP]&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;W&lt;/strong&gt;ork &lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt;n &lt;strong&gt;P&lt;/strong&gt;rogress) to the MR title, GitLab prevents it from being accidentally merged to the master branch until the diff has been discussed and reviewed by the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heather started with a first review of the post for general formatting and style according to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/gitlab-com/blog-posts/blob/master/STYLEGUIDE.md&#34;&gt;Style Guide&lt;/a&gt;, made a patch to correct some line breaks, and then assigned it for technical review to Kamil, author of the GitLab Runner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kamil made some comments and asked some questions; I responded and committed an updated draft, which updated the MR. These changes were reviewed, and the process continued until the post was ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At that point, all that was left to do was &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/gitlab-com/www-gitlab-com/merge_requests/1567#note_4185659&#34;&gt;remove the &lt;code&gt;[WIP]&lt;/code&gt; comment from the MR&lt;/a&gt;, and the post was ready to go up on GitLab&amp;rsquo;s blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which it did, yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;closing-thoughts&#34;&gt;Closing thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever I take part in some community event, I ask myself one question:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would I participate again?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, that&amp;rsquo;s all that matters. I want to feel like I&amp;rsquo;m making a contribution, that I&amp;rsquo;m learning, and that the community I&amp;rsquo;m working with is working towards some positive change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contributing to GitLab, even with just a small blog post, feels that way. In fact, it&amp;rsquo;s only increased my interest in moving my own projects to their service, and working with them towards improving GitLab however I can, be it bug report or blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, maybe I should start learning Ruby to contribute even more. 🤔&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On this week&#39;s hiatus</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-this-weeks-hiatus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-this-weeks-hiatus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While I don&amp;rsquo;t have much to post here this week, I have been writing a technical article over the last couple of weeks. The final draft was submitted yesterday and, barring any unexpected changes or delays, it should be published next week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been an interesting experience, and I intend on discussing it for next week&amp;rsquo;s instalment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until then, I&amp;rsquo;m trying to post fun little items and interesting links to &lt;a href=&#34;http://breakbeforemake.com&#34;&gt;Break Before Make&lt;/a&gt; more often, so feel free check check that out. 😊&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On methodologies</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-methodologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-methodologies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking a bit about people and some popular techniques that they use to try to improve the quality of their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specifically, I wonder if successful application of &lt;a href=&#34;http://gettingthingsdone.com/&#34;&gt;GTD&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youneedabudget.com/learn/guide/learn-to-prioritize&#34;&gt;YNAB&amp;rsquo;s rules&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;http://tidyingup.com/&#34;&gt;KonMari&lt;/a&gt;&amp;mdash;essentially, the curation of stuff (life, money, possessions)&amp;mdash;might be self-selecting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Curation is maybe a bit of a weak description. These are &lt;em&gt;methodologies&lt;/em&gt; for the processing of inputs with the goal of (typically measurable) progress towards a desired state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Mind like water&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;roll with the punches&amp;rdquo; may sound hand-wavy and zen-like, but it&amp;rsquo;s the result of discipline and rigour. I&amp;rsquo;m a pretty methodical person who does well with ritual and routine, so weekly reviews and giving every dollar a job &amp;ldquo;makes sense&amp;rdquo; to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder, though, if some people just aren&amp;rsquo;t naturally wired to ease into methodologies like these. In the same way that some people get comfortable faster with programming or geometry concepts than others, maybe there&amp;rsquo;s something to the way we&amp;rsquo;ve gotten used to parsing the world that makes it easier for methodical types to successfully apply methodologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; believe that programming or geometry is beyond the grasp of some subset of people because of their personality type or what-have-you. For some, the learning process needs to be adapted to better suit their understanding of things. For others, maybe practice makes perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the same is true of methodologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;rsquo;m struggling to understand or apply a concept, I look for one of two things: a re-framed explanation of some principle, or some kind of community support. YNAB does a great job of this, with their free classes, their community forums, and their blog. GTD does this with personal coaching and communities that build off of the system&amp;rsquo;s flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s probably why they have staying power, rather than just being some fad &lt;em&gt;life-hack&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On heroes and patient zeroes</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-heroes-and-patient-zeroes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-heroes-and-patient-zeroes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I rarely get sick, and when I do, it seldom lasts more than 72 hours. Having just recently gotten over a nasty cold, however, I have a couple of thoughts on the matter of working through cold and flu season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inevitably, there will always be someone who feels that they &lt;em&gt;can&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt;, for whatever reason, afford to take a sick day. So they load up on decongestants, fight their way in to the office, where they basically fill a seat with their butt, a trashcan with their snotty tissues, and their workplace with their germs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, in many cases, our patient zero may legitimately feel that their paycheck is threatened by them taking a sick day. This is a failure of their corporate culture: if you&amp;rsquo;re going to get fired for catching a cold, you&amp;rsquo;re going to get fired for myriad other reasons. Resign yourself to that fact, stay home, and maybe start looking for something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some others, it&amp;rsquo;s a point of pride to show how responsible and diligent they are by coming in and struggling through the day. Look at how hard they try. Poor thing. They should be home resting, but instead they came in because they&amp;rsquo;ve got work to do. What a team player. What a hero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a jackass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because no matter how careful they are keep the environment hygienic, they become a transmission vector for whatever they&amp;rsquo;re carrying. Which means their coworkers will get sick. Got a coworker with a depressed immune system? Welp, they&amp;rsquo;re screwed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a saying about the fine line between heroism and stupidity. This is a fine example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay home. Get well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have the energy for it, maybe keep up with some email just to stay abreast of what to expect when you get back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But energy is probably in short supply. You simply can&amp;rsquo;t be productive, efficient, and creative when your head is packed full of mucus. Don&amp;rsquo;t try; you&amp;rsquo;ll frustrate and stress yourself out even more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So: Netflix and sleep. Plenty of fluids. NyQuil is my personal weapon of choice in the battle for my sinuses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you start feeling better&amp;mdash;and if the work you do allows for it&amp;mdash;maybe do some work from home. Maybe crank out some of the tasks that are more like project overhead. Or take advantage of a quiet home to concentrate on some strategic or creative work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, this isn&amp;rsquo;t possible for everyone. Point is, stay home until you&amp;rsquo;re ready&amp;mdash;and you&amp;rsquo;re no longer contagious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, come back and catch up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s almost never anything so urgent that the business will go bankrupt if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have your constant attention. This fact is diametrically opposed to the point of view that some managers have. Again, this is a failure of corporate culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I digress: the point is, you&amp;rsquo;re back, you&amp;rsquo;re well-rested, and you&amp;rsquo;re ready to tackle your inbox. You&amp;rsquo;re operating at peak levels. You &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; plow through that backlog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I know that I can say these things because I&amp;rsquo;m lucky to have a pretty generous (if unspoken) sick-day policy. Our team works hard and we&amp;rsquo;re evaluated on what we get done, not the hours we put in. As a result, my stress levels don&amp;rsquo;t go through the roof at the first sign of a sore throat because I might be getting sick&amp;mdash;I just deal with getting better, then get back to work, rather than letting the stress make it worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More businesses should follow suit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On local personalities</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-local-personalities/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-local-personalities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The January 28&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; episode of Under The Radar, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.relay.fm/radar/12&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apps With Personality&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, left me thinking about just &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; software from bigger software publishers tend to be more… well, bland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of it surely comes down to the design-by-committee (or, in the worst case, design-by-accountants/lawyers) way of working that David and Marco alluded to, but I think there&amp;rsquo;s something else worth considering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every business-school student has heard the (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.snopes.com/business/misxlate/nova.asp&#34;&gt;actually false&lt;/a&gt;) Chevy Nova &amp;ldquo;legend&amp;rdquo;, whereby GM execs scratched their heads in trying to figure out why sales of the car were so poor in Latin America. It serves as a warning against moving your business into foreign markets without doing your homework first. In 2016 parlance, it speaks to the importance of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inclusion_(value_and_practice)&#34;&gt;inclusivity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While words that are homonyms across tongues may be the low-hanging fruit of localization, &amp;ldquo;personality&amp;rdquo; may be one of the most difficult. The personality created for an inanimate object often comes from cultural significance that may not be universally understood. Some of the animism described in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://konmari.com/en/&#34;&gt;KonMari method&lt;/a&gt;—thanking your shoes for a long day of supporting you, for example—just doesn&amp;rsquo;t translate well in Western consumer/capitalist society, where race-to-the-bottom market economics has associated the shoe with a thing to be disposed of, not thanked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the podcast, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetcarrot.com/weather/&#34;&gt;Carrot Weather&lt;/a&gt; was rolled out as an example of an app with strong personality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it is. That maniacal AI/robot has a charm a that keeps some users (myself included) coming back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how easily can that be localized? Even with good translations for the spoken quips, things like the secret-location Easter eggs are hard. Some might be universally understood, like the Moon, and some pop-culture references (see: Star Wars) might be &lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt; universal, but is Mount Doom meaningful to someone in Ulaanbataar?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And therein lies the rub. An indie developer that wants to inject &lt;em&gt;strong&lt;/em&gt; personality in an app often doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the resources to localize said personality to all regions in which it will sell, and a large company will probably want to invest those resources elsewhere—especially with profitability on the App Store being what it is these days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the former designs something as a result of their cultural context, with whatever lack of universality that may result. The latter &amp;ldquo;blands down&amp;rdquo; their design, in an effort to find some lowest common denominator.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On reading lists</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-reading-lists/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-reading-lists/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about adding a second kind of post to this site every week: a selection links that I found to be an interesting read during the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More specifically, I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about maybe three to five links, with a few words of my own commentary. Those links might be to freshly-published items, or they may be an interesting article from an archive somewhere. I don&amp;rsquo;t really know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I do know, is that I come across a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of thought-provoking, inspiring, or fascinating pieces of writing, and I want a more permanent place to share them than the Twitter firehose, or the Facebook walled garden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To that end, I&amp;rsquo;ll be moving my own writing to a Monday post, and a link post on Fridays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More to come…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On focus</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-focus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;I&amp;#39;ve been allowing myself to get too distracted by random projects. It&amp;#39;s time to cull that list and redouble my efforts on the key projects.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Angelo Stavrow (@AngeloStavrow) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AngeloStavrow/status/691000171539214336&#34;&gt;January 23, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Years ago, as part of an engineering internship prep course, I had to do a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.myersbriggs.org/&#34;&gt;Myers-Briggs personality test&lt;/a&gt;. The results indicated that I&amp;rsquo;m an &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ENFP&#34;&gt;ENFP type&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the MBTI was &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vox.com/2014/7/15/5881947/myers-briggs-personality-test-meaningless&#34;&gt;proven to be mostly malarky&lt;/a&gt;, one thing that keeps coming up about ENFP types is that they have trouble with follow-through. From the profile I received as a result of the test:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;An ENFP needs to focus on following through with their projects&lt;/strong&gt;. This can be a problem area for some of these individuals. Unlike other extraverted types, ENFPs need time alone to center themselves, and make sure they are moving in a direction which is in sync with their values. ENFPs who remain centered will usually be quite successful at their endeavours. &lt;strong&gt;Others may fall into the habit of dropping a project when they become excited about a new possibility&lt;/strong&gt;, and thus they never achieve the great accomplishments which they are capable of achieving.&amp;rdquo; [emphasis mine]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of whether the test is BS or not, there&amp;rsquo;s some truth to what they&amp;rsquo;re saying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not that I &lt;em&gt;can&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; focus. I can sit and hack away at a problem for hours, unconsciously suppressing signals from my body telling me to eat or go to the bathroom. If the task at hand is interesting enough, I will become fully engrossed in doing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;However&amp;mdash;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve identified some impediments to my own ability to focus and follow-through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of cool stuff to try out there. Off the top of my head, I have at least four app ideas in various stages of completion sitting in my &lt;code&gt;Developer&lt;/code&gt; folder, and at least a couple more in a Someday/Maybe category in OmniFocus. Given that it can be a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; more fun to start a new project than to udpate and maintain an old one, a certain level of discipline&amp;mdash;saying no, specifically&amp;mdash;is important to keep things on track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not all projects are engrossing. Maybe the challenge isn&amp;rsquo;t quite right for my level of competence, so rather than entering a state of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flow_(psychology)&#34;&gt;flow&lt;/a&gt;, I end up either discouraged or bored. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s a clerical kind of task that I just don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; like doing, even if the end goal would improve my life&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe the end goal just feels insurmountable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe I&amp;rsquo;m just trying to start a new habit, and I just don&amp;rsquo;t remember to act on it because it&amp;rsquo;s foreign to my daily routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those kinds of projects, it helps me to keep my head in the game, and my eye on the prize, so to speak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s something satisfying about seeing yourself chip away a goal. Here, automation can actually be a source of failure, if it prevents you from getting the kind of feedback that keeps you moving in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, I try to use the dopamine hit of checking off a to-do item, and I like to provide myself with progress reports. That way, my focus is driven by &lt;a href=&#34;http://lifehacker.com/281626/jerry-seinfelds-productivity-secret&#34;&gt;the motivation to keep a streak going&lt;/a&gt;, which is infinitely more effective for me than just &lt;em&gt;doing what I gotta do&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The GTD system uses the weekly review as one such measure, although sometimes that feels more like you&amp;rsquo;re just making sure nothing&amp;rsquo;s slipping through the cracks, rather than checking how far along you&amp;rsquo;ve gotten towards completing the project. I find it useful to track some numbers (but only when appropriate&amp;mdash;be careful of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/McNamara_fallacy&#34;&gt;the McNamara fallacy&lt;/a&gt; here) as a more quantitative measure of progress:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How many issues have I closed towards that milestone?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How am I doing on funding my Christmas expense budget?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How&amp;rsquo;s my pace improving when I go jogging?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Periodic reminders are another good tool, especially for things like starting a new habit. I use a daily reminder to get myself to work on blog posts, and another to make sure I write in my journal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I really like &lt;a href=&#34;http://balancedapp.com/&#34;&gt;Balanced for iOS&lt;/a&gt; as a way to track this, by the way.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting tools aside, at the end of the day, getting to  focus is about managing time and attention. Even with Someday/Maybe lists and reminders and weekly reviews, the one immutable law is that you&amp;rsquo;ll only ever get 24 hours in a day. If you try to cram too many &lt;em&gt;things&lt;/em&gt; into too little &lt;em&gt;time&lt;/em&gt;, there&amp;rsquo;s no opportunity to focus, because you&amp;rsquo;re forcing yourself to switch contexts too often, or you&amp;rsquo;re cutting back on sleep, or you&amp;rsquo;re probably feeling too overwhelmed to &lt;em&gt;stay on target&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the best things about a good  task management system is that you don&amp;rsquo;t have to feel committed to anything you throw in your inbox. It&amp;rsquo;s just a staging area where you can try on an idea, let it percolate, and&amp;mdash;if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;fit&lt;/em&gt;&amp;mdash;flush it down the toilet. Stop wasting mental bandwidth on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if it does &lt;em&gt;fit&lt;/em&gt;, and it&amp;rsquo;s just on of a select few, then it&amp;rsquo;s easier to keep on top it and follow through.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On moving preparations</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-moving-preparations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-moving-preparations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A short break from the usual posts for a bit of site news: by the end of February, I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to have completed the move of this site over to a static-site generator called &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few reasons for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I&amp;rsquo;m ready to leave Squarespace. It&amp;rsquo;s not that there&amp;rsquo;s anything really &lt;em&gt;wrong&lt;/em&gt; with their service. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty reliable, their customer service is great, and it&amp;rsquo;s generally pretty easy to use. It&amp;rsquo;s just that it&amp;rsquo;s overkill for what I need (a simple blog), and while they&amp;rsquo;re constantly bringing out new features, those features aren&amp;rsquo;t really of interest to me&amp;mdash;the features I &lt;em&gt;would&lt;/em&gt; be interested in paying for just don&amp;rsquo;t seem to be rolling out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, while some basic customization is available to base-plan users, it just can&amp;rsquo;t compare to the level of customization available to a roll-your-own, hackable, static-site generator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, Hugo will be the basis for another project I&amp;rsquo;m slowly putting together, so this will be good practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I will probably be re-architecting the way URLs are set up, Hugo has an &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/extras/aliases/&#34;&gt;awesome built-in feature for handling redirects&lt;/a&gt;, so all the old links should continue working. Comment will probably go away, which is fine, because there really aren&amp;rsquo;t many. Going back to &lt;a href=&#34;https://disqus.com/&#34;&gt;Disqus&lt;/a&gt; is an option, but I&amp;rsquo;m really interested in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.civilcomments.com&#34;&gt;Civil Comments&lt;/a&gt; too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll follow up when the move is complete.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On expectations</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-expectations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-expectations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two weeks ago, &lt;a href=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/blog/2016/1/1/on-fresh-starts&#34;&gt;I wrote&lt;/a&gt; that I wanted to write more&amp;mdash;primarily by posting to the blog once a week, and by writing in a journal daily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, the journal has been a success. I haven&amp;rsquo;t missed a day, because it&amp;rsquo;s easy: I launch &lt;a href=&#34;http://dayoneapp.com/&#34;&gt;Day One&lt;/a&gt; on a device, and just write. I don&amp;rsquo;t limit myself to certain topics, I don&amp;rsquo;t use any tags, I don&amp;rsquo;t add photos, and I certainly don&amp;rsquo;t worry about length. Four words, four sentences, four paragraphs&amp;mdash;it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Easy wins. Much happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing here on a regular basis, however, has been more stress than success. It&amp;rsquo;s not for a lack of things to say: as it stands, I&amp;rsquo;ve got four files in various stages of completion sitting in my drafts folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what&amp;rsquo;s making it so hard for me to get those done and uploaded?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, part of it is that it&amp;rsquo;s a bit more involved to write and post to the blog. I do it from my computer, at my desk, rather than from wherever I might have a web-connected device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But more importantly, I think I feel more pressure to write &lt;em&gt;for an audience&lt;/em&gt;, rather than just &lt;em&gt;for me&lt;/em&gt;. And that imagined audience has &lt;em&gt;expectations&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so I try to push myself to meet those imagined expectations. Because THINKPIECES.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then there&amp;rsquo;s that weekly deadline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which means that by 6:30AM Friday morning, I found myself posting something that just didn&amp;rsquo;t feel quite &lt;em&gt;done&lt;/em&gt;. I mean, it was okay, and it meant that I could check off the task as completed, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really satisfied with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Side note:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using &lt;a href=&#34;http://balancedapp.com&#34;&gt;Balanced&lt;/a&gt; as a motivator for new habits that I want to cultivate. It&amp;rsquo;s been working well for me, and I like that those little habits live outside of my GTD workflow.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t set any kind of length objective for these posts, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to start pushing back against the feeling that I need to get 500+ words out every week. The longer drafts that I have, I&amp;rsquo;ll work on periodically, and post them when they&amp;rsquo;re &lt;em&gt;ready&lt;/em&gt;, rather than forcing them to be &lt;em&gt;done&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while they&amp;rsquo;re getting ready, I&amp;rsquo;ll write short(er)-but-sweet posts on something I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about, or that take the place of a tweetstorm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because quality over quantity is more than just a platitude, but showing up every week is important too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On happiness</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-happiness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re now a week in to the new year. As I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;a href=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/blog/2016/1/1/on-fresh-starts&#34;&gt;mentioned before&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;m not really one for resolutions, but here&amp;rsquo;s something that&amp;rsquo;s been on my mind lately. A proposal, of sorts, in two parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be the person that makes you happy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be the person that makes other people happy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the how and why of it, as I see it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Part&amp;nbsp;1&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Part&amp;nbsp;2&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Situation&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;❌&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;❌&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;This is the worst-case scenario. You&amp;rsquo;re not happy. You&amp;rsquo;re surrounded by people who aren&amp;rsquo;t happy, which can perpetuate a downward spiral. It gets dark here, but on the bright side, there&amp;rsquo;s lots of room for improvement too.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;❌&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;✔️&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re making others happy at the expense of your own happiness. Maybe even acting as an enabler. Who knows? Alternatively, your friends may be jerks. One way or the other, this is a huge energy sink. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit clichéd and simplistic, I know, but ultimately, you have to be okay with who you are before you can &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; make things better for others.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;✔️&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;❌&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re happy, but no one else is. You might be a jerk, but probably you&amp;rsquo;re caught up in something and you&amp;rsquo;re maybe a little less mindful than you want to be. Alternatively, you may be surrounded by people who need your help. A word of caution here, though: it&amp;rsquo;s possible that you&amp;rsquo;re just not equipped for this task. Take care that this situation doesn&amp;rsquo;t change into the one described above.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;✔️&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;✔️&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;This is the best place to be. You&amp;rsquo;re making strides towards being the person you want to be, and you&amp;rsquo;re helping others win too. Good on ya.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tricky part is that these scenarios are fluid. Some days everyone&amp;rsquo;s happy, and some days no one&amp;rsquo;s happy; on most days, though, it&amp;rsquo;s one of those mutually-exclusive-happiness situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things always come back to centre, but it&amp;rsquo;s important to keep in mind that &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt; define where that centre is. And when we&amp;rsquo;re having a hard time in a tough situation, centre can feel like the worst of these scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Screw it all, I don&amp;rsquo;t give a crap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or: I&amp;rsquo;m burning out, but at least I&amp;rsquo;m making other people happy, and they probably appreciate that, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the time, we define where we live, emotionally-speaking, without even thinking about it. We fixate on an argument we had with a loved one, or a project we really can&amp;rsquo;t be arsed about at work, and the feelings we have about that particular thing spread to other areas of our life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happiness is a fleeting thing, and always will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out, though, that if you listen hard enough, there&amp;rsquo;s always a little voice that&amp;rsquo;s providing real-time metrics on your progress towards becoming the person that makes you happy. That internal director&amp;rsquo;s commentary takes the form of a great night&amp;rsquo;s sleep, or a bout of heart palpitations, or a morning of inexplicable crankiness, or even a day of insufferable boredom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is mindfulness. It lets us step in and interrupt the signal chain between &lt;em&gt;what&amp;rsquo;s happening to us&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;how we feel about it&lt;/em&gt;, and make the appropriate course corrections. It&amp;rsquo;s the compass you need, to guide you back to a centre that makes you feel like the person you want to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I struggle with this, but the more thought I put into these goals&amp;mdash;the more mindful I am of them&amp;mdash;the better I do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On fresh starts</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-fresh-starts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-fresh-starts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A lot of people seem to think that New Year&amp;rsquo;s resolutions are a waste of time. While I agree that any day is a good day to make changes, I also know that I like things in neat and tidy little parcels, and a year is a very nice little short- to medium-term period of time for setting goals, and revisiting them to see how you did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t try anything like that for 2015. While I feel the year was pretty good on the whole, this year I&amp;rsquo;d like to make it a little more official, make some of those goals (and their results) public record here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in no particular order, here are some goals for this year:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post something here every Friday.&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m not setting any kind of length for now—it&amp;rsquo;ll be hard enough to get back into the habit of writing regularly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post to a journal at least once every day.&lt;/strong&gt; Again, no stated length; even a sentence will do. Thankfully, &lt;a href=&#34;http://dayoneapp.com&#34;&gt;DayOne&lt;/a&gt; makes this really easy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make real progress towards my Mac app.&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve been kicking around an idea for years now, and by year end I&amp;rsquo;d really like to have at least a first beta available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contribute to open-source projects.&lt;/strong&gt; Without setting a goal for a number or frequency of pull requests, I&amp;rsquo;d like to participate more in some OSS projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get in better shape.&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m not overweight, I&amp;rsquo;m not underweight, and I&amp;rsquo;m generally in good shape, but there&amp;rsquo;s always room for improvement—in my case, that&amp;rsquo;ll come from discipline in getting to the gym. To that end, I&amp;rsquo;m really thinking about making some of my fitness-tracker profiles public.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t an exhaustive list by any means, as I have some personal and private goals that I&amp;rsquo;d also like to aim for, but it&amp;rsquo;s a good start. I&amp;rsquo;ll revisit this list every quarter and see how I&amp;rsquo;m doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I hope that the next 366 days are happy, healthy, and fruitful for you. On with the show.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On automation</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/on-automation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a firm believer in automation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Computers are great environments for this—scripting languages (and convenient utilities that leverage them, like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.noodlesoft.com/hazel.php&#34;&gt;Hazel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://smilesoftware.com/textexpander&#34;&gt;TextExpander&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://ifttt.com/&#34;&gt;If This Then That&lt;/a&gt;) make it trivial to organize, queue, and execute all kinds of tasks that otherwise time away from more enjoyable things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• • •&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life can be a bit harder to automate. It can get  expensive, too, because automating real-life tasks tends to require both hardware &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; software, working in concert, to manipulate the physical world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of that, a lot of the automation we look at isn&amp;rsquo;t really something that saves us any significant amount of time, because what&amp;rsquo;s being automated isn&amp;rsquo;t real work. Probably the most obvious example of this are home-automation tasks like lighting schemes, motorized blinds, and auto-adjusting thermostats. Sure, they&amp;rsquo;re convenient, but they&amp;rsquo;re luxuries. They don&amp;rsquo;t have a meaningful impact in the quality of our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love my universal remote, but it&amp;rsquo;s not a time- or work-saver. Not really.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• • •&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; automation technologies, however, that do provide real savings on time and work. Here, however, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to fall into the trap of automating work that would otherwise be beneficial to do manually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an example: I own a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.irobot.com/For-the-Home/Vacuum-Cleaning/Roomba.aspx&#34;&gt;Roomba&lt;/a&gt;, but not a dishwasher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve got a long-haired cat whose contributions to the household mainly consists of bundles of fur that roll down hallways like tumbleweed in the desert. My wife is pretty allergic to it, so we need to keep on top of the vacuuming or things go south quickly for her. Given that it&amp;rsquo;s an otherwise hated chore, we got ourselves a Roomba to patrol our flat for dander and dust bunnies on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, doing dishes—while not exactly pleasant—is a chore that allows me to settle into my thoughts, and has been shown to reduce stress levels in studies. I&amp;rsquo;ll concede that it&amp;rsquo;s not that hard to deal with, as we&amp;rsquo;re only two people, but nonetheless this feels like work that&amp;rsquo;s worth making time for. It&amp;rsquo;s not uncommon for me to come up with ideas, or solve problems that I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on, while wrist-deep in suds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s sort of a mandated creative-thinking time, if you will. Given how hectic our lives can be, why would you want to automate that away?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Festina lente</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/festina-lente/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2014 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/festina-lente/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Make haste slowly.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or, if we forsake brevity for clarity: get it done quickly, but not so urgently that thoroughness is sacrificed for speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once committed to action, it is desirable to move swiftly, decisively; but to do so without having completed one&amp;rsquo;s due diligence&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; is foolhardy at best, and dangerous at worst.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li class=&#34;footnote&#34; id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The hard part in all of this, of course, is know when the diligence is done and the planning can begin. Look too hard for the perils and pitfalls, and you&#39;ll never get the thing underway. Don&#39;t look hard enough, and you might find yourself starting from scratch—or abandoning the project completely.&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; title=&#34;return to article&#34;&gt; ↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Or, just strive to be the best</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/or-just-strive-to-be-the-best/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2014 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/or-just-strive-to-be-the-best/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The only way to do great work is to love what you do.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure to whom the above quote is attributed, but I don&amp;rsquo;t buy it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only way to do great work is to put in 100% of your attention and your effort, follow a thorough PDCA&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; methodology, and understand that the quality of your work depends entirely on your will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get that this quote is supposed to be an inspirational call to action, but thinking that you can only excel at things that you love is equal parts reductive and defeatist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll concede that it&amp;rsquo;s easier to mail it in when you don&amp;rsquo;t especially care for the work you&amp;rsquo;re doing, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you&amp;rsquo;re forced to be mediocre about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t make excuses. Make great things—regardless of your passion for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li class=&#34;footnote&#34; id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Plan &amp;rarr; Do &amp;rarr; Check &amp;rarr; Act: one of the tenets of a quality management system.&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; title=&#34;return to article&#34;&gt; ↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Due dates, do dates, and die dates</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/due-dates-do-dates-and-die-dates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2014 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/due-dates-do-dates-and-die-dates/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;A calendar is, at its essence, just a list. But how effectively that list is used can transform your calendar from a mostly-neglected application to a finely-tuned productivity tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key to this transformation is the proper care and feeding of your calendar. It is a garbage-in-garbage-out system, so it&amp;rsquo;s crucial that we make sure that we only add items to our calendar that belong there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For &lt;a href=&#34;http://gettingthingsdone.com&#34;&gt;GTD&lt;/a&gt; acolytes like myself, it feels like we rise and fall by the quality of our lists. After all, these various context lists pretty act like an outboard brain, telling us what we&amp;rsquo;re supposed to be doing at the given moment, so if we throw action items onto them willy-nilly, and if they&amp;rsquo;re not tended to regularly, it all falls apart, becoming a system that you don&amp;rsquo;t use because you can&amp;rsquo;t trust it. Specifically, this means that anything you place on your calendar, you should treat as a promise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But—and this is the key—don’t use your calendar for task management, as it’s really meant for time management&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. I really like an idea &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.merlinmann.com&#34;&gt;Merlin Mann&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; has &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.43folders.com/2008/02/14/time-attention-talk&#34;&gt;discussed&lt;/a&gt;, where he suggests that productivity is not just about managing your time, but also about managing your attention. Let &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.omnigroup.com/omnifocus&#34;&gt;Omnifocus&lt;/a&gt; (or whatever) handle your tasks, and let your calendar handle your time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a good &lt;a href=&#34;http://5by5.tv/mpu/179&#34;&gt;Mac Power Users episode&lt;/a&gt; on calendar management that got me thinking about how I use mine, and how I deal with time management in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;due-dates&#34;&gt;Due Dates&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It feels like including this field in a task-management system is probably one of the most polarizing conversation in GTD-Land&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. I go back and forth on it, myself (a &lt;em&gt;time required&lt;/em&gt; field makes more sense, maybe, because you can then sort your context lists according to how much free time you have).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most tasks, however, adding due dates&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;makes little sense in the real world;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;clutters your calendar needlessly (it&amp;rsquo;s no longer a “hard landscape” of real appointments);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;undermines the flexibility of your workflows if you strictly follow these due dates;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;undermines the reliability of your system if you don’t; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;adds busywork that would probably be unnecessary if you were doing better reviews of your projects and lists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, sometimes a date of some sort makes sense for a particular task. So I tend to use the due-date field as one of two things: a &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; date, or a &lt;em&gt;die&lt;/em&gt; date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-dates&#34;&gt;Do Dates&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do dates&lt;/em&gt; are for tasks that absolutely need to get done on a certain day or by a certain time. Should these go on your calendar? Renewing your driver&amp;rsquo;s license, for example, is just such a thing, but you&amp;rsquo;ll get a notice ahead of time reminding you of this, so you probably don&amp;rsquo;t need another reminder in your calendar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What about your wife&amp;rsquo;s birthday? Sure, that may be on your calendar, but did you give yourself a heads-up early enough to shop for her present, or will she be getting another six-pack of premium carwashes and a box of four-year-old chocolates that you had to pick up at the gas station on the way home because it was a long day at the office and it was the only place still open?&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Maybe that&amp;rsquo;s a good candidate for a do date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A better one is passport renewal. For myself, it&amp;rsquo;s on a five-year renewal period, but I don&amp;rsquo;t get any kind of reminder, and if it has expired, I&amp;rsquo;ve only got six months to get it done if I want the &amp;ldquo;simplified&amp;rdquo; renewal option. But it still requires a few things, like getting a photo taken, locating my old passport, completing a form, and mailing it out, so it&amp;rsquo;s a project, and I really don&amp;rsquo;t want to find myself with an expired passport two weeks before a business trip. So while I&amp;rsquo;ll have a 5-year review cycle for my &amp;ldquo;renew passport&amp;rdquo; project, I&amp;rsquo;ll go ahead and add some do dates to those tasks that are more time sensitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;die-dates&#34;&gt;Die Dates&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Die dates&lt;/em&gt; are for tasks that are far less important—optional, even—but that still have some kind of time sensitivity to them. While it&amp;rsquo;s not paramount that you actually complete the task (like an item on your &lt;em&gt;Someday/Maybe&lt;/em&gt; list), you may only have a limited amount of time to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking into concert tickets, for example, is just such a thing. Popping into a store that&amp;rsquo;s having a sale on iTunes cards is yet another. It&amp;rsquo;s okay if these things get skipped, but they &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; in your system for a reason, and if you don&amp;rsquo;t give yourself a reminder, you&amp;rsquo;re likely to miss the opportunity because of its limited-time availability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;footnote&#34; id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There are more good tips [here][6] and [here][7].&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; title=&#34;return to article&#34;&gt; ↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;footnote&#34; id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Don&#39;t call him a productivity guru. But do listen to his [podcast, Back To Work, with Dan Benjamin][8].&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; title=&#34;return to article&#34;&gt; ↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;footnote&#34; id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;GTD-Land&lt;/i&gt; is a magical place where apparently everyone is so fantastically efficient at getting things done that they can sit back and nitpick the minutia of every GTD tool out there. For 18 hours per day. Every day. Weekends and holidays included.&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; title=&#34;return to article&#34;&gt; ↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;footnote&#34; id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Bonus points may be awarded if she doesn&#39;t own a car and/or you forgot that she&#39;s allergic to chocolate.&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; title=&#34;return to article&#34;&gt; ↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finishing moves</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/post/finishing-moves/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2014 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/post/finishing-moves/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Remember Mortal Combat?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was (and I guess still is) a fighting game whose claim to fame, when it was released in arcades back in the 90s, was the idea of a &amp;ldquo;finishing move&amp;rdquo;—if you beat your opponent, you had the opportunity to do a special attack, sending them off to meet their maker in a rather bloody fashion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I don&amp;rsquo;t condone violence, the idea of a &amp;ldquo;finishing move&amp;rdquo; made me think a little bit about how I tend to deal with recurring tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Task:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;Vacuuming&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Type:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;Chore&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pull tiny &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Dyson-DC26-Multi-Compact-Canister/dp/B004AQ591K/ref=sr_1_cc_1?s=aps&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1396999803&amp;amp;sr=1-1-catcorr&amp;amp;keywords=dyson+city&#34;&gt;Dyson City vacuum cleaner&lt;/a&gt; out of its cramped storage space&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give the flat a good once-over&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replace vacuum cleaner in aforementioned cramped storage space&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comment:&lt;/strong&gt; Older apartments have next to no storage space, which means that we needed a small but effective vacuum cleaner. The Dyson City is positively lilliputian, but with this space-saving design comes an equally tiny cannister to hold all the cat-hair tumbleweeds that our remarkably-fluffy cat can produce at an alarming rate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finishing Move:&lt;/strong&gt; Always empty cannister just before putting the vacuum cleaner back into storage. This way, it&amp;rsquo;s always ready for the next round of a chore we both hate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Task:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;Getting a haircut&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Type:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;Errand&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arrive at purveyors of fine haircuts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enjoy the courtesy massage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engage in banter about comic books and movies with hairdresser while getting haircut&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pay for services rendered&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leave purveyors of fine haircuts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comment:&lt;/strong&gt; My hair grows like a weed. Coarse, wavy, rebellios weeds, to be specific. Given that my appearance needs all the help it can get, I go in for a haircut every three to four weeks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finishing Move:&lt;/strong&gt; So that I don&amp;rsquo;t have to give it a second though, I always schedule my next appointment while paying on my way out, and put it into my calendar immediately. This way, I don&amp;rsquo;t have to set any reminders to make an appointment, nor do I have to worry about looking like a sheepdog.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could go on, but I think you get the idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key is that when I&amp;rsquo;ve got some kind of task that I know will pop back up on my to-do list at some point in the future, I ensure that I build into my workflow some kind of finishing move that makes my life a little bit easier the next time around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, it&amp;rsquo;s not a big deal to call up and make a haircut appointment, but my brain is put to much better use doing creative and enjoyable things, like solving problems at work or focusing on the people that are special to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also no big deal to empty a vacuum cleaner before you start vacuuming, but it&amp;rsquo;s such an unpleasant thing to do in the first place that I don&amp;rsquo;t want to give myself &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; reason to stall. It&amp;rsquo;s friction, when it comes to productivity, friction is failure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About this site</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This is my personal website and blog. If you&amp;rsquo;d like to know more about what I&amp;rsquo;m up to at the moment, check out my &lt;a href=&#34;https://angelostavrow.com/now&#34;&gt;now&lt;/a&gt; page. You can get in touch with me via &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:contact@angelostavrow.com&#34;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;philosophy&#34;&gt;Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site includes a &lt;code&gt;philosphy.txt&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;../philosophy.txt&#34;&gt;Check it out&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-you-ll-find-here&#34;&gt;What you’ll find here&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoy writing, which is good, because I’m terrible at it and they say that the only way to improve is through practice. From here on out, this is where my writing will live. I write about pretty much whatever topic comes to mind, but it&amp;rsquo;s typically focused on development, of both the personal and software persuasion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;privacy-policy&#34;&gt;Privacy policy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t use any analytics on this site. I tried anayltics on a personal site and frankly, the data and trends weren&amp;rsquo;t interesting to me. If you like what you read, I hope you&amp;rsquo;ll come back. If not, I&amp;rsquo;ll try to do better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you email me, I&amp;rsquo;ll read your email! By extension, that means I will have a record of your email address.  I won&amp;rsquo;t use it for anything other than replying to you without your explicit, written consent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;affiliate-links&#34;&gt;Affiliate links&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to use affiliate links to generate revenue. They… didn&amp;rsquo;t. I don&amp;rsquo;t use affiliate links any more. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to go back and remove them from old posts, but if I&amp;rsquo;ve missed any, please &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:contact@angelostavrow.com&#34;&gt;let me know&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-stack&#34;&gt;The stack&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site is statically generated using &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; and runs a custom theme I built called &lt;em&gt;indigo&lt;/em&gt;. It’s still a work in progress, so please let me know if anything seems amiss. I apologize in advance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;typography&#34;&gt;Typography&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site makes use of the following wonderful typefaces:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bboxtype.com/typefaces/FiraSans/#!layout=specimen&#34;&gt;Fira Sans&lt;/a&gt; for heading text&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://practicaltypography.com/charter.html&#34;&gt;Charter&lt;/a&gt; for body text&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tonsky/FiraCode&#34;&gt;Fira Code&lt;/a&gt; for monospaced text&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Licenses are included in the indigo theme&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;static/fonts&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/now/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Inspired by Derek Sivers&amp;rsquo; &lt;a href=&#34;https://sivers.org/nowff&#34;&gt;now&lt;/a&gt; page, this page gives you a little bit of information on what I&amp;rsquo;m up to these days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now I am…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Living in: Montreal, Canada. 🇨🇦&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Part of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://manuscript.com&#34;&gt;Manuscript&lt;/a&gt; engineering team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building: This site&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; theme — it&amp;rsquo;s almost there!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading: &lt;em&gt;The Nordic Theory of Everything&lt;/em&gt;, by Anu Partanen (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.anupartanen.com/the-nordic-theory-of-everything/&#34;&gt;🔗 &amp;rarr;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Last updated August 13&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;, 2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Status updates</title>
      <link>https://angelostavrow.com/updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://angelostavrow.com/updates/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-micro-blog-https-angelo-micro-blog&#34;&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://angelo.micro.blog/&#34;&gt;micro.blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This content is typically syndicated to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AngeloStavrow&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type=&#34;text/javascript&#34; src=&#34;https://micro.blog/sidebar.js?username=angelostavrow&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>